Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
We are gathered here today
to immortalize in song
the life and untimely death
of a great legend.
- Rango.
- So sit back, relax,
and enjoy your low-calorie popcorn
and assorted confections
while we tell you the strange
and bewildering tale of a hero
who has yet to enter his own story.
Crunchy, creamy, cookie,
candy, cupcake.
Okay, everybody,
let's take it from the top.
The stage is set,
the night moist with apprehension.
Alone in her chamber, the princess
prepares to take her own life.
"It is far better to nourish worms
than to live without love."
She reaches for the poisoned chalice.
Meanwhile, the wicked Malvolio
plots his ascension to the throne
while her aging father lies gravely ill.
"Yes, I am gravely ill."
"Hark, who goes there?"
'Tis I, the much-anticipated hero,
returning to rescue
his emotionally unstable maiden!
Unhand her, you jailers of virtue,
or taste the bitter sting
of my vengeance!
The sting of my...
Dr. Marx?
Dr. Marx,
I'm not getting anything from you.
People, we've talked about this.
Acting is reacting.
Victor, you were wooden!
There, I said it.
Mr. Timms? You were good.
Perhaps a little too good.
What's that, Victor? My character's
undefined? That's absurd.
I know who I am.
I'm the guy, the protagonist, the hero.
Every story needs a hero.
I mean, who else is better qualified
to bask in the adulation
of his numerous companions?
The stage is waiting.
The audience thirsts for adventure.
Who am I?
I could be anyone.
I could be the sea cap'n
returning from a mighty voyage
to reclaim his mechanical arm!
Or I could be the rogue anthropologist,
battling pythons down in the Congo!
Down, Chongo, down!
And if you desire romance,
I will become the greatest lover
the world has ever known!
I couldn't help but notice you
noticing me noticing you.
You know, the womens find me
uncomfortably good looking.
But you seem remarkably at ease.
Stop it. No, really.
Well, if you must. What are you doing?
That tickles. Are those real?
That's it! Conflict.
Victor, you were right.
I have been undefined.
People, I've had an epiphany.
The hero cannot exist in a vacuum!
What our story needs is an ironic,
unexpected event
that will propel the hero into conflict!
Mr. Timms?
That's right! You!
Don't be shy. Come on.
It's okay.
That's it, a little closer.
Good.
I won't bite you.
I need a little help here.
Are you okay?
I must get to the other side.
The other side? You mean, just now,
that was you crossing the road?
That's why the...
Why'd you do that?
This is my quest. He waits for me.
What? Who?
The Spirit of the West, amigo. The one.
They say he rides an alabaster carriage
with golden guardians to protect him.
What are you talking about?
Enlightenment.
We are nothing without it.
Nothing? Your delusional quest
just ruined my life!
I had an incredibly complex
social network going!
Highly sophisticated friends!
I was very popular!
Friends? I don't see no friends.
You are a very lonely lizard.
Look, I need water, hydration.
My teeth are chapped.
I need lotion.
I'm down to one layer of skin already.
Pretty soon,
I'm going to start seeing my insides.
Not unlike what you've got going there.
Listen, I can't survive
in the desert, okay?
I... I don't belong here.
That may be true, but here you are.
Now help me up
and I will help you find what you seek.
- You will?
- And perhaps more.
Quickly. I must get back to my quest.
- You mean you've done this before?
- Yes. Many times.
Come, come. That's it, pull my finger.
The Spirit is waiting for me.
Okay, okay.
Okay. That's not going to work.
I must get to the other side.
Why don't you just wait
until there are no cars coming?
It's not so easy as it looks.
What?
Is a metaphor.
There's another one!
I knew it.
You need a little help, amigo?
I think the metaphor broke my spleen.
The path to knowledge
is fraught with consequence.
I'm just looking for the path to water.
If you want to find water,
you must first find Dirt.
Dirt.
Destiny, she is kind to you.
Tomorrow is Wednesday.
The water comes.
At noon, the townspeople gather
for a mysterious ritual.
A town? You mean, with real people
and everything? Where?
A day's journey. Follow your shadow.
You want me to just walk out
into the desert?
That's the way.
Okay. So you're saying
there's a town, a real town,
not a metaphor town.
Go on. It's okay.
Okay.
Well, then, I'm going.
I am leaving the road now!
I'm walking into the desert!
Alone!
We all have our journeys to make!
I will see you on the other side.
Welcome, amigo
To the land without end
The desert and death
Are the closest of friends
We sing of his courage
In magnificent song
But pay close attention
He won't be here long
As the birds pluck his eyes
The sun bleaches his bones
See his entrails get scattered
Watch him lose his cojones
Here in the Mojave Desert,
animals have had millions of years
to adapt to the harsh environment.
But the lizard? He is going to die.
"Four score and seven years ago,
our fathers..."
- Don't move.
- What?
- Don't move!
- Not moving.
Not moving.
Try to blend in.
Blend in? What do you mean?
Blend in.
What are you saying?
- Too late.
- No, no. It's not too late!
I'm blending! I'm a blender!
Hey, calm down! What are you doing?
Stop moving!
Try not to look conspicuous.
- What are you doing?
- I'm blending.
- Go blend somewhere else.
- Don't distract me.
- No room at the inn.
- It's an art, not a science.
- Find your own hiding place.
- No, this is good.
Here she comes! You better run, Mojito!
- What? I thought you said, "Don't move."
- That was before. Now, you run.
Oh, hey. Proboscis.
Testy.
Please, no, please. I have vertigo!
My glands are swelling!
Please, no.
You! I'll kill you! You stupid lizard!
Get out of there.
I'm going to strangle your huevos!
Big bird! Big bird!
No, wait! Come back! I was just kidding!
- Come on, we're friends, right?
- I don't know you!
- Lizards, frogs...
- Find your own hiding place!
- We're practically related!
- No room at the inn!
- Come on, move over!
- You're not my friend!
I'll let you kiss my sister!
You son of a...
Where are your friends now, amigo?
Get your slimy-webbed phalanges
off my boots!
Sorry.
I got a bead on you, stranger.
So you get up real slow
lessen you want to spend the better part
of the afternoon
putting your face back together!
- No, ma'am, I don't.
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
- I'm asking the questions here!
Our town is drying up.
We're in the middle of a drought.
Now someone's dumping water
in the desert!
It's a puzzle of undeterminable size
and dimension,
but I intend to find out
what role you playing in all this.
- Role?
- What are you involved in?
Well, I'm glad you asked.
I've got two one-acts, a mystery
and a musical I've been gestating.
I got the words, I'm just working on
the melody right now. It's like a...
I think it's gonna be a western.
A monkey got a cracker
His mother was a slapper
She'll be coming 'round the mountain
in the rain
You ain't from around here, are you?
I'm still working on it.
So, what's your name?
- Beans.
- That's a funny kind of name.
What can I say?
My daddy plumb loved baked beans.
Well, you're lucky
he didn't plumb love asparagus.
What are you saying?
I mean,
I enjoy a hearty puttanesca myself,
but I'm not sure that a child
would appreciate the moniker.
My daddy was a great man, even if
he did exhibit a proclivity for legumes.
- Spicy.
- You're eating his ashes!
You carry his remains?
No, his ashes. He loved to smoke.
They never found the body.
Well, I'm sure he had his reasons.
- What are you implying?
- Nothing.
My daddy was never near
that mine shaft.
He'd been sober for over a month!
And for you to insinuate that he would
abandon his parental responsibilities
at a delicate time in my personal
development is an affront to my sense...
Miss Beans?
Miss Beans? Hello?
Hello?
And until the people of Andromeda Five
return him safe and sound,
I will not sell my ranch!
- What... What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- What am I doing?
- You're cuddling me.
- You were frozen.
- I was not.
Yes, you were. You stopped talking.
It's a defense mechanism.
Actually, lots of lizards have it.
You're making that up.
So, you gonna die out here,
or you want a ride into town?
No, no, no. Yeah. No. Yes, please.
Thank you. Sorry.
Today's Wednesday.
Wednesday's when we all get to it.
So who are you, really?
Well, I'm a man of many epithets.
There's my stage name, my pen name,
my avatar.
I had a pseudonym once,
but I had it legally changed.
And so the stranger,
seeking companionship,
finds the woman,
much like the sirens of ancient times
luring him to his certain demise.
...nom de plume, I have a CB handle.
I'm actually one of the few men
with a maiden name.
Whoa! Well, here we are.
Right.
Well, I sure do appreciate this,
Miss Beans,
- and if there's ever anything that I...
- Get on up!
Okay, then!
See you, Beans.
You heading out, Jim?
Well, we gave it our best shot.
We had to sell out.
Can't grow no crops without no water.
Bye, now!
What is it?
What was that for?
You're funny looking.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you're funny looking, too.
- That's a funny-looking shirt.
- That's a funny-looking dress.
- You got funny-looking eyes!
- You got a funny-looking face!
You're a stranger.
Strangers don't last long here.
Here's your beans, Beans.
I'm gonna need some more feed, too,
Willie.
Now, Beans, you owe me three quarts
already. I can't give you more credit.
But I'll have what I owe you at noon.
You don't understand. It's Mr. Merrimack
down at the bank. He cut off all credit.
Hey, Beans! Beans!
You know that there fella?
Hey, Beans! Miss Beans!
Nope.
Hey, Beans!
Hey.
Right. Blend in. Yeah, blend in.
I'd like a glass of water.
He wants a glass of water!
Make it a double!
Give him the spittoon!
Cactus juice. That's what we got.
Hey, there, fruit cup.
You're a long ways from home, ain't ya?
Who exactly are you?
Who am I?
I could be anyone.
What's the matter?
You missing your mommy's mangos?
As a matter of fact, I am.
But not as much as
your daddy's cooking!
Exactly where did you say
you were from?
Me? I'm from the West.
Out there, beyond the horizon.
Past the sunset.
The Far West.
Yeah, that's right, hombres.
The place I come from,
we kill a man before breakfast
just to work up an appetite.
Then we salt him, and we pepper him.
Then we braise him in clarified butter.
And then we eat him.
- You eat him?
- That's what I said!
Hell, I seen things make a grown man
lose control of his glandular functions!
You spend three days in a horse
carcass, living off your own juices.
It'll change a man. Oh, yeah.
Had a few extra aces in this deck,
gents. Just the way I like it.
So, no, my hirsute little rodent friend,
I am not from around these parts.
You might say I'm from everywhere
there's trouble brewing
and hell waiting to be raised.
You might say
I'm what hell's already raised up.
Name's
Rango.
Are you the fella
that killed them Jenkins brothers?
Killed them with one bullet.
Don't get no deader.
All seven of them?
That's right.
All seven of them.
Exactly how you do that, Mr. Rango?
You know, I'm glad you asked me that.
And I will be happy to tell you how.
But you're all gonna have to listen up!
Because this is where it gets
complicated.
That'll close out your account,
Mrs. Oats, two gulps and a swig.
Hands off, Mordecai! That's what's left
of your college education!
I don't rightly have
no other choice, Beans.
Times being so hard,
we just can't give no more credit.
But this here is a bank.
This is where you keep the water.
Beans, you've been like a niece to me
ever since your daddy
did not fall drunk down a mine shaft.
I've tried to protect you and others
from certain realities.
But that... Well...
- Mr. Merrimack?
- Realities are bearing down.
Mr. Merrimack!
Are you all right?
Beans, I need to show you something.
- That's all that's left?
- And this here is the reserve!
I don't know if you've noticed,
but folks just ain't making deposits
on a Wednesday no more!
Mr. Merrimack, if I don't get some water,
I'm gonna lose my ranch
and you're telling me
that's all that's left in the whole town?
Now that just don't make no sense.
Now, listen.
Someone is dumping water
in the desert.
I seen it with my own eyes.
Water in the desert?
Was this during
one of your special times?
No.
Well, we can all dream,
but this is the reality.
Why do you think so many people
are selling out? They just can't make it.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
Well, I suppose
we could talk to the Mayor.
I hear he's been helping people out
in this time of crisis.
The Mayor?
He may be our only hope.
Bullet hits a shovel, ricochets back
towards number three,
and that's when the roof caved in,
igniting the thermos
of pure grain alcohol
instantly vaporizing his bodily form,
leaving nothing but a charcoal statue
and a high-pitched squeal.
Hold on, there. That's only six.
What happened to number seven?
Number seven?
Hell, he died of infection.
- Seven men!
- One bullet!
Drinks all around!
Dance for me, Sod Buster!
- Yes, dance like a chicken!
- That's right! Dance!
You got corn in your ears, mate?
You don't pay the mortgage,
you don't own the land!
- That's basic real estate law, my friend.
- Quid pro quo!
If I see your face in this town again,
I'm gonna slice it off and use it
to wipe my unmentionables.
Mind the beak.
And don't come back!
What are you all gawping at?
Hey, Bad Bill,
there's something I got to tell you!
What is this?
You know who that is, Bill?
That there's Rango!
Yeah, he ain't afraid of you!
He ain't afraid of none of you.
Killed them Jenkins brothers.
- Done it with one bullet, Bill.
- All seven of them!
Is that right?
Let me get that before you...
No. Oh, I know. Here.
Just take care of that for you.
There. All better.
T.O. T.O. Just a second.
All right, now listen!
I'm going to give you fellas
one last chance to reconsider!
And if you don't want to reconsider
I might consider reconsidering myself.
Now that's what I'm talking about. Yeah.
All right, now listen up!
Things are going to be different
around here now that Rango's in town.
Got some new rules!
I want my shoes shined every morning,
my coffee hot, Danish on the side.
Whatever you do,
don't look me in the eye.
Stay out of my peripheral vision!
- It's Rango.
- What's he up to?
He ain't afraid of nobody.
He's telling that bird what's for!
And when you see me coming,
stand aside.
I take large steps and I don't want
none of you hayseeds
getting your bodily fluids on my boots!
Of course, there is no need for violence,
as long as we stick together,
work as a team.
So I want you all to come outside now
and line up single file
while I take a brief intermission!
What's he doing now?
I think it's a number two.
Never mind.
Take a look-see over here!
Well, look at him now!
He's chasing after that hawk!
Give him hell, Rango!
- Did you see that?
- He killed that thing!
What do you think, Doc?
This hawk is dead!
Shoot, I say we cook that right up.
He did it with one bullet!
Just like he said!
It's about time
we had a hero around here.
One who ain't in a pine box.
I think it's time he met the Mayor.
You hear that, Rango?
You're going to meet the Mayor!
Let's hear it for Rango!
And so the stranger basks
in the adulation of his new friends,
sinking deeper into the guacamole
of his own deception.
When is he going to die?
Soon, compadre. Soon.
My land is not for sale!
I came here to save my land, not sell it!
I'm sure there's something reasonable
we can work out if you just talk to him!
Beans! Where are you going? Beans?
The Mayor will see you now.
Water, Mr. Rango, water.
Without it,
there's nothing but dust and decay.
But with water there's life.
Look at them, so desperate to live,
they'll follow it anywhere.
That's the immutable law of the desert.
Control the water
and you control everything.
But I don't have to tell you that being
a true man of the West, as you are.
Oh, yeah. The West is the best.
This is from my private stock.
Vintage rainwater
from the Great Deluge.
Not Noah's deluge.
Good heavens, I'm not that old.
I guess power has its privileges.
You make a good point, son.
But with privilege comes responsibility.
Hell, I was mayor here
before there was a Dirt!
And I may be
just a sentimental old turtle
but I think there's a future for this town.
And I hope you'll be part of it.
- To Dirt!
- To Dirt.
You see them, Mr. Rango?
All my friends and neighbors?
It's a hard life here. Very hard.
Do you know how they make it through
each and every day?
They believe.
They believe it's going to be better.
They believe that the water will come.
They believe against all odds
and all evidence
that tomorrow will be better than today.
People have to believe in something.
Right now, they believe in you.
Pick it up, Mr. Rango.
Your destiny awaits.
People have to believe in something.
It's almost noon. Is everything ready?
Yeah. But he might be a problem.
He's not a problem, William.
He's a solution.
It just don't make no sense.
This whole town is drying up,
and the Mayor is the only one
who don't seem to be affected.
Doesn't that make you
just a wee bit suspicious?
And what about that water
I saw out in the desert?
All right! No need to incite anxiety.
I'll inquire about the Mayor.
But if you really feel
there's some conspiracy occurring,
I suggest you take it up
with the new sheriff.
This is going to be good. Hey!
Watch that needle there.
Not too tight.
I want to leave room for some pucker!
That's good.
Oh, easy there, tiger.
- A little up and back?
- I don't think so.
Have you got French cuffs with that?
Excuse me, Sheriff Rango.
I want to talk to you.
Hey, Beans,
what do you think of the new duds?
I got a 1 0-gallon hat
marked down from 15.
- That's nice.
- Have you met Angelique?
- Hello, Beans.
- Hello, Angelique.
- Tart.
- Floozy.
- Trollop.
- Excuse me, Mr. Rango.
I will blow that ugly right off your face!
I was just thinking that...
You want the old John Hancock,
do you?
- Well, here. Hold this.
- Sheriff Rango, this isn't a social call.
There's a bullet in there.
I know about the shindig this afternoon.
- I ordered myself some right fancy duds.
- Sheriff, I'd like to file a...
- Mr. Rango!
- Oh, you, too? No problem.
- Here, let me just...
- I need you to investigate...
You know, Beans, I bet you clean up
real nice, you put a little effort into it.
- What?
- Now, remember, son,
stay in school, eat your veggies,
burn everything but Shakespeare.
- Who's Shakespeare?
- Sheriff Rango,
if that is your real name.
I am trying to save my daddy's ranch,
which is on the verge
of an agricultural meltdown
while you're playing patty-cake
with this here trollop!
Sad, really. Such a drab little thing.
Why does she do that?
- It's a survival reflex.
- Her switch is just broken.
Well, that's an inconvenience.
It is not a rash! It is a birthmark!
I did it again, didn't I?
Did what?
Let me ask you something.
Did anybody here mention
what happened to our last sheriff?
Pardon, but may I ask you...
Excuse me, may I ask you...
The last sheriff... Pardon me.
Where is everybody going?
What exactly happened to the...
All day
I've faced the barren waste
Without the taste of water
Cool water
Old Dan and I
With throats burned dry
And souls that cry
For water
Cool
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Clear water
This is a heck of a hoedown
you got going.
Still working out those steps.
So, is this considered
normal civic behavior?
Every Wednesday, just like clockwork.
You kill bird.
Yeah. Matter of fact, I did.
Bird dead. Snake come.
Snake?
He means Rattlesnake Jake, Mr. Rango.
He never comes to town 'cause
he's scared of that hawk.
But he might come now.
Can I have your boots
when you're dead?
No!
And I ain't got no problem
with this Rattlesnake Jake.
That's just what Amos said.
Amos?
You got any gold fillings?
My fellow Dirtonians.
I welcome you to our great day
of deliverance. Hallelujah.
- Hallelujah!
Acolytes, prepare the holy spigot!
We have a newcomer
amongst us today, my friends.
A man I think needs
little introduction to you
so bold has been his entry
into our fair society.
Mr. Rango, would you step forward?
The time has come, my friends.
The time that was foretold!
- Hallelujah!
The sacred time!
The time of destiny!
- Hallelujah!
The time of deliverance!
It is the time of hydration!
- It's his fault!
- It's the newcomer!
- Burn him!
- He's a witch!
I get his boots!
My friends, my friends!
Temper your frustrations.
Times will be tough from now on.
Sacrifices will have to be made.
But if I can help in any way,
please know that my door is always...
Hold it, hold it!
Now, this whole thing
stinks three ways to Sunday.
First the bank's run dry
and now this here spigot?
The bank's run dry?
- What's she talking about?
- She said there's no water in the bank!
This is all we have!
We can't give it all out!
That was my rehydration account!
None of that civil disobedience
in my town, thank you very much.
Thank goodness you're here, Sheriff.
Things were getting out of hand.
Come right in.
Let me have a gander at the source
of the societal discontentment here.
Mercy.
All right, listen up! I've been thinking
and I believe I've figured something out.
You folks have a water problem!
Now just pay attention, everybody.
I'm trying to make a point here.
Let's say this fella here
were to take a drink of water.
Just one little drink.
No harm, no foul, right?
And you!
You're just as dried up and parched
as a jackrabbit in July.
So you belly on up
and take you a double shot!
Stay with me.
What do you think happens then?
Why we'd all be drinking!
And before you know it,
there wouldn't be any more water.
And then where would we be?
We'd be thirsty.
Real thirsty.
We'd turn on each other
like a bunch of animals!
Now look here.
We have got six days of water.
We have got five days...
As long as we've got water,
we've got ourselves a town.
Sheriff Rango is right.
As long as we have this water,
we have some hope.
And you can all take it from me.
My 100% full-time employment
from this moment on
will be to protect
our precious natural resource.
Ain't no one gonna tango
with the Rango.
Evening, ladies.
Evening, Sheriff.
And don't you come back!
Hold on there, Gordy. You get back
in there and you assert yourself,
and I think you'll find the people of this
here town to be surprisingly hospitable.
Thank you, Sheriff.
What? Not you again!
I stand corrected.
- This ain't the bank.
- I told you, Jedidiah!
Hold it right there!
- Who's that?
- It's the Sheriff!
Get them hands up
where I can see them!
Just as I suspected.
Prospecting without the authorized
equipment. Don't move a muscle.
Prospecting?
Now, you got your shovel,
pickaxe, Benadryl, loofah,
assorted snacks, some puzzle books
and you're gonna need a permit.
- Loofah.
- Ezekiel, Jedidiah!
What the Sam Hill's going on up there?
I've had polyps removed
smarter than the two of you!
Hell's fire, this ain't the bank!
Pappy, the Sheriff is standing right here,
helping us out.
Gonna give us a permit for prospecting.
That's right, sir. Just doing my duty.
The lonely constable on his rounds,
keeping an eagle eye out
for mayhem and malfeasance.
Does he look like he sounds?
Well, Sheriff,
if we was to hit the mother lode,
being prospectors and such,
where would we deposit said annuity?
Here in the town of Dirt,
we happen to have
the finest financial institution
this side of the Missouri.
Protected morning, noon and night
by yours truly.
Much obliged.
The bank's been robbed!
Good Lord, the bank's been robbed!
What's going on?
- It's gone! The water's all gone!
- What'd he say?
He said the bank's been robbed!
Dr. Marx! I'm on fire! Embrace me!
The bank's been robbed, the town is dry
"We'll die of thirst," the people cry
He promised to protect the vault
The water's gone, it's all his fault
All right, folks, stand back,
clear the area.
This is a crime scene now.
Secure the perimeter, dust for prints,
check for fibers, scan for DNA.
I want a urine sample from everyone.
And get me a latte.
And don't mix up the two.
What's this?
"Prospecting Permit."
I'll take that. Material evidence.
What are we gonna do now, Sheriff?
- We need that water.
- We're all going to die!
My friends, we all know
what we have to do now.
That's right.
We all know what we have to do now.
- And that would be?
- Form a posse.
Form a possum!
A posse.
Now, we're gonna be doing this
in an orderly fashion.
First off, does anybody here know
how to use a firearm of any kind?
All right, then.
What do we do now, Sheriff?
Now we ride!
Where are we going?
What?
Now, as my deputy, you'll be in charge
of all tracking and finding of villains,
utilizing your well-developed
Injun-uity, no offense taken.
So which way do you think they went?
You want to sniff the air or commune
with a buffalo or something?
Oh, you're good.
I'm depending on you, Spoons.
You got a little tobaccy
in the beard there.
Always good to have a medical man
along, Doc.
Reptiles got to stick together, right,
my brother?
I'm an amphibian.
Ain't no shame in that.
You sure you're
fit for duty there, soldier?
Well, you got a little something
in your eye there.
Oh, that? That there's conjunctivitis, sir.
It's hereditary.
Well, I'm glad to hear
it's not contagious.
Now, just wait a cotton-picking minute!
A posse ain't no place for a...
Never mind.
Hold on there, little sister.
Someone's gonna have
to look after the town while I'm gone.
Can I gut-shoot someone?
Let's put a pin in that.
Sheriff, you're going to bring
that water back, aren't you?
Count on it, little sister.
- Which way do we go, Sheriff?
- There's tunnels everywhere.
Whole town's perforated with them.
She got more holes in her
than a painted lady on a porcupine.
Hey, my daddy took me to her place.
Not what I expected.
How'd them fellers
find the bank, anyway?
Gentlemen, if we can just
stay on task here.
Sheriff! Over here!
- Would you look at that?
- Like seeing the face of God.
Amen, brother.
I remember when it used to flow
every Wednesday.
Those were the halcyon days.
Must be a reason she quit on us.
Whatever the reason,
something is controlling this here water.
What do you say, Sheriff?
Clearly, the robbers came
from this direction.
I say we track this pipe
back to its hydraulic origin
and apprehend the culprits
behind this aquatic conundrum.
- What'd he say?
- I think he said follow the pipe.
- He said follow the pipe.
Sure is humid down here.
Yeah, it's activating my piles.
I had a goitre removed once.
Looked like Tony Bennett
stepping out of the shower.
Shoot, I put that on a tortilla.
Whatever you do, do not look down.
- What is this place?
- It's an aquifer.
What's an aquifer?
Well, it's for aqua.
Well, it's empty now.
That's a big one.
- It's the end of the line.
- Don't go no further.
Well, now that there is a pipe.
It's got to be connected to something.
You talk too much.
Why don't you put a cork in it?
Why don't you put a cork...
Tell you where the sun don't shine.
Your mama did.
I'll cook her right up.
You two just don't get it, do you?
Someone or something
is messing with our hydration
and that pipe
has got something to do with it.
I thought
we was following bank robbers!
We're experiencing a paradigm shift.
I'm gonna shift the features on your face
if you don't shut up!
Go ahead and try!
Quiet, you savages! Stop your rattling.
You're affecting my cogitation.
Whoa! I got it. Snuff out them torches.
Sure enough.
Smart thinking there, feller.
- Start climbing.
- Get your foot out of my face!
Not bad, huh, Beans?
You keep thinking like that,
your hat's gonna catch on fire.
Well, you know, you get on a roll,
you just...
Hot, hot! Burn.
Poor things.
All they wanted was a little water.
Cactus dying of thirst. It don't bode well.
- Hey, look what I found!
- What you got there?
- I saw that first!
- Hey, that's mine!
Give me that!
It's empty anyway.
I knew that.
Where'd you find that?
Sheriff! You're going to want to see this!
It's Mr. Merrimack from the bank.
What's he doing here?
- Everybody stand back.
- All right, let me see.
Looks like them varmints shot him
in the back.
No, this man wasn't shot.
He was drowned!
- Drowned?
- In the middle of the desert?
What a way to go.
Well, now, whose boot prints are those?
That's interesting.
The ground's still wet.
I suppose we should bury him.
I don't know. Birds got to eat, too.
Circle of life!
Sheriff.
Will you say a few words?
Yeah. Yeah.
Dearly beloved.
We are gathered here today
to honor this man.
Mr. Merrimack,
you have the right to remain silent.
Speak now or forever hold your peace.
Amen.
- Amen.
Hey! What's that dad-gum Indian doing?
I see you're consulting with the spirits.
No, I'm moulting.
Means I'm ready to mate.
I'll keep that in mind.
Cactus fruit.
Ah, yes. The ancient cactus fruit.
I believe your people use it
as seasoning
when preparing your native dishes.
Also natural laxative.
Pick up trail.
Three men heading west.
One blind, one with
enlarged prostate, riding sidesaddle.
- What did he say?
- They're riding sidesaddle.
- We're whispering.
- What'd he say?
Someone's got a bad valve.
All right, which one of you fellers
needs a check-up?
Awkward.
What exactly are we going to do now?
Now we ride!
That means we're riding now!
This moment.
Marshmallows remind me
of going camping with my daddy.
I could eat them all night long.
Of course he did make me cough them
back up again for breakfast.
This one time,
I coughed up an entire Dalmatian.
That ain't nothing.
I coughed up a whole tribe of pygmies.
They started looking at me weird.
I remember them.
They was quite friendly.
I found a human spinal column
in my fecal matter once.
You might want to get that looked at.
Pass the beans, Beans.
- Sheriff?
- No, thanks.
Mr. Rango? Can you tell us
about the Spirit of the West?
- Yeah, tell us about that.
- Is it true what they say?
Yes, the Spirit of the West!
The eternally unattainable ideal.
They say he rides in
an alabaster carriage
with golden guardians to protect him.
But he only appears to those
who have undertaken an epic quest!
And have made it
to the other side.
The other side of what?
It's a metaphor.
My eye!
That's gonna heal right up.
Sheriff? What are you going to do
about Rattlesnake Jake?
What? Where?
Sorry about that. Word is
you come against him once or twice.
Yeah.
Jake. You mean my brother.
- Your brother?
- That's what I said!
But he's a snake and you're a lizard.
Well, Momma had an active social life.
Did he ever bite you?
Sure enough did. Look at that baby.
Go ahead, you can touch it.
That's interesting.
That there's a belly button.
Luckily, I'm immune to his venom.
Put some in my coffee
just to give it a little tang.
Is it true he's only scared
of them hawks?
Them's what we call
his natural predator.
All this talk of that serpentine devil
is putting my quills on edge!
I ain't sleeping tonight. No, sir.
Don't you all worry about a thing.
Come tomorrow, we'll locate that water
and return to a hero's welcome.
Friends, before we bunk down
I'd like us all to join hands
for a moment,
say a few words
to the Spirit of the West.
That's a good idea.
Ain't always spoken rightly to you,
Spirit of the West.
But tonight I want to thank you for
bringing Sheriff Rango into our lives.
It's a hard life we got.
Sometimes I don't know how
we're gonna make it.
But somehow, Sheriff Rango
makes me think we will.
We needed a brave man
and you sent us one.
Nice to have someone
to believe in again.
Thank you, Spirit of the West. Amen.
- Amen.
Just checking.
- It's a little cold tonight.
- Thank you.
You ever feel like those things
are looking at you?
That's a Spanish dagger.
But around here,
we just call them the Walking Cactus.
Walking?
There's an old legend they actually
walk across the desert to find water.
When I was a little girl, I'd stay up late
watching them, to see if they'd move.
I thought if I could follow them,
they'd lead me to someplace wonderful.
Someplace with enough water
for everyone.
Night after night, I watched them.
I never saw them move.
But you're still watching.
Who doesn't want to find
someplace wonderful?
We'll find the water, Beans.
I promise you.
That's such a lonely sound.
You ever get lonely?
Sometimes.
I can't imagine it. You're such a charmer
and everyone likes you so much.
- I never made friends easy like that.
- No?
No, we're pretty isolated
out there on the ranch,
sort of like being sealed up
in a little box.
Don't really see a lot of folks.
I wouldn't know what that's like.
There someone special
in your life, Rango?
There used to be.
But she couldn't keep her head.
Besides, my life's too dangerous
for that kind of thing.
You know, it's an awful solitary
existence out there on the prairie.
Riding the ranges and the suchlike.
Beans?
I'm gonna skin you alive, boy! I'm gonna
whup you like a red-headed stepchild!
Choleric varmints, ain't they?
Dysfunctional family. Need intervention.
What's that coming?
It's the water.
I have a plan, and each and every one
of you has a part to play.
What do I do?
Spoons, you got
the most important job of all.
You stay up here on the ridge,
and if anything goes wrong,
you give the signal.
Hey, Beans.
What size dress you wearing?
- He got it!
- Hallelujah!
- He found the water!
- You did it, son.
Well, actually...
Why can't you be all brainy
like your brother?
Pappy, about that water.
There's something I gots to tell you.
Hush up, now. Somebody's coming.
Good sirs, gracious good afternoon
to thee and thee and thee.
May I present Madame Lupone's
Terpsichorean Troupe
of Traveling Thespians!
- What is that?
- I think they's thespians.
Thespians?
That's illegal in seven states!
The stage is set. The princess
prepares to take her own life.
I yearn for love.
Meanwhile, the lone sentry
stands watch at the castle gate.
Stands watch at the castle gate...
Hark! Who goes there?
This plot is highly predictable.
Quiet! This is my favorite part.
Arriving to great fanfare
'twas her aged father,
strucketh by Cupid.
Prithee, unhand my fair daughter
and reach for the...
- Line?
- "Reach for the sky!"
What was that?
Must be that immersive theater.
We got you surrounded!
You and your entire family get
your hands up where I can see them.
My entire family?
Grits and spit and collard greens
Waffle chitlins, monkey brains
Refried bones and booger blood
Pickled eggs and flaps of mud
It's a full house.
Looks like we're gonna have ourselves
a good old-fashioned standoff.
I'll have you know, you're not looking
at our entire contingent.
What's that supposed to be?
That's the signal.
That's the signal!
Something must have gone wrong!
So something's supposed to happen?
I am open to suggestions.
Run!
Get on the wagon!
Should we have ourselves
some sport, chill'ens?
I likes it when they run.
Maybelle, give the holler!
Looks like we made it!
That audience was quite responsive.
Yeah, well, I think that
chromosome pool is about dried up.
We got bats!
Here! You drive.
Looks like there's gonna be
soup tonight!
Come on, let's get some!
What in tarnation?
Don't shoot the water!
Jedidiah! It's time for
the Alabama squeeze box!
Okay, Pa!
I am sensing hostility.
Incoming!
Hello!
Goodbye!
Lasso that swine!
I suggest we take evasive action!
I suggest you shut up and shoot!
- What happened to the Sheriff?
- He had a previous engagement!
Boseefus, give them some gumbo now!
What was that? Go check it out!
What is it? Is there a problem?
You could call it that.
Headache.
Is that all you got?
That wasn't altogether unpleasant!
Eat lead!
Here, hold these.
Get your hands off me!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Jump!
It's impossible.
It can't be. It's empty.
There's no water!
No water?
Then what the hell we been fighting for?
Sir, you have defiled and desecrated
the very sustenance of our livelihood!
I think that there fella in the purty dress
is the Sheriff.
That's the same fellow what give us
a prospecting permit?
- A what?
- Irrelevant! Obfuscation.
You and your kin are under arrest
for bank robbery
and the murder
of our beloved financial advisor
Johannes Merrimack the Third,
AKA, Fluffy Joe.
Sheriff, we didn't kill nobody.
We done tunneled into that vault,
but there weren't nothing in it.
Somebody done robbed that bank
before we robbed it.
Then where'd you get this here jug?
That's what I been trying
to tell you, Pappy.
I found it in the desert.
Then why in tarnation
did you bring it here?
Hold on! You're saying this here jug
was empty when you found it?
That's right.
I don't believe a word of it.
- Let's hang them, Sheriff!
- String them up!
Who'd dump water in the desert?
Wouldn't be the first time.
It's a puzzle!
It's like a big old mammogram!
What's going on, Sheriff?
I don't know.
But I'm going to strip away this mystery
and expose its private parts.
You and your kin are coming with me.
They're coming!
Here they come!
Looks like they got them robbers.
Where's the water?
There weren't no water.
Where is he going?
He's going to see the Mayor.
He's got to be pleased with that.
That's a good one, boss!
That's interesting.
I do apologise for the shoes, Mr. Rango,
but there's a certain protocol
to this game, you understand.
I'm a bit of a stickler for protocol.
Well, that's good, 'cause you got
a few questions to answer
and I've got my own protocol.
But why would anyone dump water
in the blooming desert?
It does seem a bit naive, taking the word
of admitted bank robbers.
Besides, once they hang,
your job is done.
- Bravo!
- Job well done.
But what if somebody did rob the bank
before they got there?
And who would do that, Mr. Rango?
I was hoping you could tell me.
That sounds marginally
near to an accusation.
Take it any way you like.
Something you said keeps rattling
around in my frontal lobe.
What's that?
"Control the water
and you control everything."
Come now, Mr. Rango.
You attribute divine power to me.
How on earth
could I possibly control the water?
You've obviously mastered this game.
Well, I've been playing it
for many years, sir.
I was here before the highway split
this great valley.
I watched the march of progress,
and I learned a thing or two.
Perhaps it's time you started
to take the long view,
begin to appreciate
the broad sweep of history.
Look out there, son.
You can almost see time passing.
What are you building out here?
The future, Mr. Rango, the future.
One day soon,
all this is going to fade into myth,
the frontier town, the lawman,
the gunslinger.
There's just no place
for them any more.
- We're civilized now.
- That's right, civilized.
That's what the future holds.
You can either be part of it,
or you can be left behind.
Is that what happened to
Mr. Merrimack? Did he get left behind?
Careful, Mr. Rango. You seem to forget
you're just one little lizard.
You seem to forget
I'm the law around these parts.
Our new sheriff has been
playing the hero for so long,
he's actually starting to believe it.
Call in Rattlesnake Jake.
But Jake's the Grim Reaper.
He never leaves
without taking a blooming soul.
Do it!
Now be still. You gotta look
presentable to meet your maker.
Death has arrived
How will the hero survive?
The Mayor has bought up
all the land in the valley,
except for your ranch, Miss Beans.
That just don't make no sense.
Without water, that land is useless.
Unless he controls the water.
Like a monkey's bladder!
Then he could bring it back
once he's bought up all the land.
But how does he control the water?
Well, you gotta spend some time
and train them.
'Cause you know monkeys, when
they do go, you rub their nose in it.
Sheriff, we got a problem.
Hold on, Beans.
That won't be necessary.
- Hang him till his head turns blue!
- Give us them robbers!
Hold on! Calm down, everyone!
Let me talk!
- Nail them to the courthouse!
- Now, calm down, everybody.
Get them out here
so we can cut off their giblets!
You, too, Spoons?
They done taken that water.
They taken everything we got!
No one's stringing anyone up.
Not while I'm sheriff.
But this is all his fault!
You said you's gonna
bring the water back.
It's just, we got no hope
without that water.
We got nothing left to believe in.
You see that sign up there?
As long as that sign says "Sheriff,"
you can believe that there's
law and order in this town.
But without law and order,
ruminate on that. Oh, yeah.
Starts out slow, like a fungus.
Somebody says a cross word.
Accusations start flying.
Neighbor turns on neighbor.
Pretty soon, we're eating our children!
And then dogs and cats
are getting together
to create all sorts of unnatural
mutant aberrations!
So, you want something
to believe in, Spoons?
Believe in me.
Believe in that there sign.
For as long as it hangs there,
we got hope.
Hello, brother.
Thirsty?
Long time, brother.
How you been keeping?
Well, you know...
I hear you been telling about how
you killed all them Jenkins brothers.
With one bullet, wasn't it?
Isn't that right?
All these good folks here
believe your little stories, don't they?
Why, they believe you're just
a stone killer, don't they?
Seems these folks trust you.
They think you're gonna save
their little town.
their little souls!
But we know better, don't we?
So why don't you show your friends here
what you're made of?
Show them who you really are.
Why don't you just pull your gun
and shoot me?
But, of course, you won't need all these.
Just one, right?
Go ahead, hero. Pull the trigger.
You got killer in your eyes, son?
I don't see it.
You didn't do any of them things
you said, did you?
You didn't kill them Jenkins brothers.
You ain't even from the West!
Are you?
- Say it!
- No.
Speak up.
I don't think your friends here heard you.
No.
All you've done is lie
to these good people.
You ain't nothing but a fake
and a coward. Isn't that right?
Yes.
- Louder!
- Yes.
Listen close, you pathetic fraud.
This is my town now.
If I ever see you again, I will take
your soul straight down to hell!
Who are you?
Who am I?
I'm nobody.
Golden guardians.
The alabaster carriage.
The Spirit of the West.
Excuse me? Mister Spirit, sir?
There's a beaut. Sometimes you got to
dig deep to find what you're looking for.
So you made it.
Is this heaven?
If it were, we'd be eating Pop-Tarts
with Kim Novak.
Yeah.
No kidding.
What are you doing out here?
Searching, same as you.
I don't even know
what I'm looking for any more.
I don't even know who I am.
They used to call you
the Man with No Name.
These days they got a name
for just about everything.
Doesn't matter what they call you.
It's the deeds make the man.
Yeah, but my deeds just made things
worse. I'm a fraud. I'm a phony!
My friends believed in me,
but they need some kind of hero.
Then be a hero.
No. No, no, you don't understand.
I'm not even supposed to be here.
That's right. You came a long way
to find something that isn't out here.
Don't you see? It's not about you.
It's about them.
But I can't go back.
Don't know that you got a choice, son.
No man can walk out on his own story.
So you made it.
That's right, amigo.
The other side of the road.
Did you just see that?
We each see what we need to see.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yeah.
It is.
Come, my friend.
I want to show you something.
Many years ago,
this entire valley was covered in agua.
Now only one question remains.
Where did it go?
They follow the water.
They follow the water! Come on!
That just don't make no sense.
Without water, that land is useless.
What are you building out here?
The future, Mr. Rango.
You can either be part of it,
or you can be left behind.
I was here before the highway split
this great valley.
I watched the march of progress
and I learned a thing or two.
Control the water
and you control everything.
Come now, Mr. Rango.
You attribute divine power to me.
How on earth
could I possibly control the water?
What now, amigo?
No man can walk out on his own story.
I'm going back.
But why?
Because that's who I am.
You got a lot of nerve showing up here,
lawman. What is it you want?
Your pappy and them boys are about
to hang for something they didn't do.
But I've got a plan.
I appreciate how difficult
this is for you, Beans.
But you're making a practical decision.
Decisions, decisions.
There's no need for any more suffering.
Your family's ranch is nothing
but a wasteland now.
Sign the deed and relieve yourself
of your father's burden.
My daddy was not a burden!
Keep your blood money
and I'll keep my land!
Do what he says or,
by all the fires of the black pit,
I'll squeeze them pretty brown eyes
out of your skull!
Now, hold on, Jake.
There's no need to...
Let me do my job! You brought me in.
Now we're gonna play this thing
out to the end!
Sign the damn paper, woman!
Go to hell!
Where do you think I come from?
Look into my eyes.
I want to see you die.
Jake!
I'm calling you out!
This day
just got a little more interesting.
Put her down.
Or what, little man?
You going to kill me?
That's just about the size of it.
- Get your filthy paws off me!
- Shut your gob!
All right, Sheriff, make your move.
Now amigos!
- Heave! Heave!
That was a bad idea.
Thirsty, brother?
Here it comes!
No. No!
It's a miracle!
Look out!
- Lookee there!
- What is that?
It's our salvation, Pa!
It's a jailbreak, boys! We're busting out!
I'm gonna blow so many holes in you,
your guts'll be leaking lead!
Well, then
it's a good thing I brought some backup.
What?
Ain't no hawk.
Ain't nothing but bats!
Stick to the plan, boys!
Let's bleed that devil dry!
It only takes one bullet.
You ain't got the nerve.
Try me.
Oh, Mr. Rango.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Hand me your gun, Sheriff.
Now, Mr. Rango.
Beans! Hold on.
Don't worry, I got a plan.
Help!
Open the door!
Okay, plan B.
Beans, you're mumbling.
All my problems taken care of
except for one.
It's a new West, Jake.
There's no room for gunslingers
any more. We're businessmen now.
Yeah, we got new hats.
Where I come from,
we call this improvisation.
You came back.
What was that?
No need to panic,
but I think you just swallowed plan B.
What?
Okay, panic time.
You and the Sheriff are more alike
than you think.
You're nothing but legends.
Pretty soon,
no one will believe you even existed.
One last bullet to kill one last outlaw.
How fitting.
Sheriff, I'm sure if we work together,
we can reach a mutually beneficial
solution to our current situation.
You better take it up with him.
One bullet.
I tip my hat to you,
one legend to another.
What was that you said?
"Pretty soon,
no one will believe you even existed."
No, Jake! No!
Rango!
You brought the water back,
just like you promised.
You really are a hero.
Well, the thing about heroes is,
whenever you...
Don't spoil it.
Right.
Well, I don't know about you all,
but I could sure go for a dip.
And so the lizard completes his journey
from humble beginnings
to the legend we sing of today.
And although he is certain to die,
perhaps from a household accident,
which account
for 65% of all unnatural deaths,
the people of the village
will honor his memory
even as they abandon their dignity.
- I'm going in.
- How about a cold one, there?
Water ain't money. Money is money.
- Well, I ain't got no...
- We're talking hard cash.
We have a problem.
Who let Snuggles in the pool again?
I really think you complete me.
Prithee, unhand my fair maiden.
- Cut. Cut. Everybody, take five.
- How can you keep missing your mark?
What's my motivation?
Oh, you kids.
What did you do that for?
I was just checking.
I hear if you get too sunburnt,
you can peel a man's face right off.
- What is it?
- That there's some human spleen.
Don't touch it.
That's the second time
that's happened to me.
This water thing's great.
I'm urinating right now.
Adult swim, next five minutes.
Stay between the buoys.
I packed your lunch. Danish is in there
and I picked the raisins out
just the way you like it.
Don't forget, your nasal spray is
in your saddle-bag...
- Beans!
- ...and your moisturizing lotion...
- Now, Beans! We've talked about this.
- Lotion?
That's for my gun. That's gun lotion.
Sheriff, where are you headed?
There's trouble down a dry creek.
Bad Bill's been acting up again.
Now, honey, you come back
with all your digits.
And don't go trying to be a hero.
Beans, you are missing the point.
I got an image to protect now.
Where's my Tic Tacs?
- I found them.
- What's going on?
Well, in order to satisfy the needs
of the collective,
the hero must abandon the self
and solidify his image as an icon
that will forever be remembered.
So, this is the sunset shot.
Give them a good one, amigo.
Ready, Excelsior?
My fellow comrades.
There will be times
when you doubt yourself.
When you feel pummeled
by the cataclysms of life,
remember this moment.
Remember me.
Know that I will be there watching you,
sometimes at inappropriate moments.
That's part of the deal.
And remember, within all of us resides
the true Spirit of the...
Let's take it from the top.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
‫نحن مجتمعون هنا اليوم لنخلّد بأغنية‬
‫حياة أسطورة سابقة ووفاتها قبل الآوان‬
‫لذا اجلسوا، استرخوا‬
‫واستمتعوا بالفشار بسعرات حرارية أقل‬
‫والحلوى المرافقة‬
‫بينما نحكي لكم قصة غريبة ومحيّرة لبطل‬
‫ما زال عليه الاندراج في قصته الخاصة‬
‫هش، قشدي، بسكويت، سكاكر، حلوى‬
‫حسنا جميعا، لنعد الى البداية‬
‫المسرح جاهز، الليل المفعم بالترقب‬
‫وحدها في الغرفة، تستعد الاميرة للإنتحار‬
‫خير لها ان تطعم الديدان بدل العيش بلا حب‬
‫تمد يدها لتمسك الكأس المسمّمة، أثناء ذلك‬
‫يتآمر الشرير "مالفوليو" لاعتلاء العرش‬
‫بينما والدها العجوز مصاب بمرض خطير‬
‫أجل، أنا مصاب بمرض خطير‬
‫من هناك؟‬
‫هذا أنا البطل المنتظر عاد لإنقاذ فتاته‬
‫المضطربة نفسيا‬
‫أفلتوها يا سجّاني الفضائل‬
‫أو تذوّقوا لسعة انتقامي المرير!‬
‫لسعة...‬
‫د. "ماركس"؟‬
‫د. "ماركس" لا أسمع منك شيئا‬
‫يا جماعة، سبق أن تحدثنا بالأمر‬
‫التمثيل ردة فعل‬
‫فكتور، كنت متصلّبا، هاك، لقد قلتها‬
‫سيد "تيمز"، كنت جيدا‬
‫ربما جيد إلى حد الإفراط‬
‫ماذا "فكتور"؟ دوري غير محدد؟ هذه سخافة‬
‫أعرف من أكون، أنا الرجل، البطل، الزعيم‬
‫كل قصة بحاجة إلى بطل‬
‫أعني، من غيري مؤهل لهذا الدور‬
‫ليتنعّم بتملّق رفاقه الكثيرين؟‬
‫المسرح بانتظاري‬
‫الجمهور توّاق للمغامرة‬
‫من أنا؟‬
‫يمكنني أن أكون أيا كان‬
‫يمكنني أن أكون قبطانا عائدا من رحلة ضخمة‬
‫لاستعادة ذراعه الآلية!‬
‫يمكنني أن أكون عالما شريدا بعلم الانسان‬
‫يتصارع مع الأفاعي في "كونغو"!‬
‫انبطح "شونغو"، انبطح!‬
‫وإن أردتم الرومنسية‬
‫سأصبح أبرز عاشق قد عرفه العالم!‬
‫مرحى!‬
‫لم يسعني سوى الملاحظة أنك لاحظت‬
‫أنني لاحظت وجودك‬
‫أتعلم؟ تعتبر النساء أن سحري لا يقاوم‬
‫لكنك تبدو مرتاحا جدا‬
‫توقف، لا، حقا‬
‫حسنا، إن كان عليك ذلك، ماذا تفعل؟‬
‫إنها تدغدغني، هل هذه حقيقية؟‬
‫وجدتها، قتال‬
‫فكتور كنت محقا، كان دوري غير محدد‬
‫يا جماعة، أدركت فجأة‬
‫أن البطل لا وجود له في الفراغ!‬
‫ما تحتاج إليه قصتنا هي حدث ساخر غير متوقّع‬
‫يدفع البطل إلى القتال!‬
‫سيد "تيمز"؟‬
‫اسمع!‬
‫هذا صحيح، أنت!‬
‫لا تكن خجولا، هيا‬
‫لا بأس‬
‫أحسنت، أقرب قليلا‬
‫حسنا‬
‫لن أعضّك‬
‫أحتاج إلى مساعدتك‬
‫هل أنت بخير؟‬
‫علي... العبور إلى الطرف الآخر‬
‫الطرف الآخر؟ أنت الذي كان يعبر الطريق؟‬
‫لهذا السبب...‬
‫لم فعلت ذلك؟‬
‫هذه مهمتي، إنها بانتظاري‬
‫ماذا؟ من؟‬
‫روح الغرب يا صديقي، الوحيدة‬
‫يقال إنها تتنقّل على متن عربة من مرمر‬
‫لها حرّاس ذهبيون‬
‫عم تتحدث؟‬
‫التنوير، نحن نكرة بدونه‬
‫نكرة؟ سعيك الوهمي قد دمّر حياتي للتو!‬
‫كان لدي شبكة اجتماعية هائلة، أصدقاء محنكون‬
‫كنت محبوبا!‬
‫أصدقاء؟ لا أرى أي أصدقاء‬
‫أنت عظاية وحيدة جدا‬
‫ساعدني على النهوض فأساعدك لتجد ما تبحث عنه‬
‫ستفعل ذلك؟‬
‫بسرعة، علي استئناف سعيي‬
‫- سبق أن فعلت ذلك؟‬
‫- أجل مرات عدة‬
‫هيا، أحسنت، اسحب إصبعي‬
‫الروح بانتظاري‬
‫حسنا، حسنا‬
‫لن ينجح الأمر‬
‫علي الذهاب في الاتجاه الآخر‬
‫لم لا ننتظر ريثما لا يعود هناك سيارات؟‬
‫ليس الأمر سهلا بقدر ما يبدو عليه‬
‫إنها استعارة‬
‫هذا واحد آخر!‬
‫كنت واثقا من ذلك‬
‫تحتاج إلى مساعدة، يا صديقي؟‬
‫أعتقد أن الاستعارة أتلفت طحالي‬
‫السبيل إلى المعرفة محفوف بالعواقب‬
‫أبحث وحسب عن السبيل إلى المياه‬
‫إن أردت البحث عن الماء، عليك إيجاد القذارة‬
‫قذارة‬
‫القدر، إنه يرأف بك‬
‫غدا يوم الأربعاء، ستأتي الماء‬
‫في الظهر، يجتمع سكان البلدة للاحتفال‬
‫بشعائر غامضة‬
‫بلدة؟ أي اشخاص حقيقيون وما إلى ذلك؟ أين؟‬
‫على مسيرة يوم من هنا، اتبع ظلّك‬
‫هل تريدني أن أسير في الصحراء؟‬
‫هذه هي الطريق‬
‫حسنا، إذا تقول‬
‫إن هناك بلدة، بلدة حقيقية وليست وهمية‬
‫هيا، لا بأس‬
‫حسنا‬
‫حسنا سأذهب‬
‫سأترك الطريق الآن!‬
‫سأسير في الصحراء!‬
‫بمفردي!‬
‫لكل منا رحلة يقوم بها!‬
‫سأراك في الجانب الآخر‬
‫أهلا بك يا صديقي‬
‫إلى الأرض بدون نهاية‬
‫الصحراء والموت‬
‫هما أعز صديقين‬
‫نشيد بشجاعته‬
‫في أغنية رائعة‬
‫لكن الزموا الحذر جيدا‬
‫لن يبقى هنا طويلا‬
‫بينما تقتلع الطيور عينيه والشمس تسفع عظامه‬
‫سترون أحشاءه المبعثرة وهو يفقد خصيتيه‬
‫هنا في صحراء "موهافي"‬
‫اعتادت الحيوانات على البيئة القاسية‬
‫على مر ملايين السنوات‬
‫أما العظاية؟ فستموت‬
‫منذ ٨٧ عاما، كان آباؤنا...‬
‫لا تتحرك‬
‫- لا تتحرك‬
‫- لا أتحرك‬
‫لا أتحرك‬
‫حاول التموّه‬
‫التموّه؟ ماذا تقصد؟‬
‫تموّه‬
‫ماذا تقول؟‬
‫- فات الأوان‬
‫-لم يفت الآوان، إنني أتموّه!‬
‫أمارس التمويه!‬
‫اهدأ، ماذا تفعل؟ اهدأ!‬
‫كف عن الحراك!‬
‫حاول عدم لفت الأنظار‬
‫- ماذا تفعل؟‬
‫- أتموّه‬
‫- افعل ذلك في مكان آخر‬
‫- لا تصرف انتباهي‬
‫- لا مكان شاغر في النزل‬
‫- إنه فن، ليس علما‬
‫- جد مخبأك الخاص‬
‫- لا، هذا جيد‬
‫ها قد أتى، اركض "موهيتو"!‬
‫- طلبت مني ألا اتحرك‬
‫- ذلك سابقا، الآن اركض‬
‫وداعا يا صديقي!‬
‫مهلا، خرطوم‬
‫متشنّج‬
‫رجاء لا، أنا مصاب بصداع، غددي متورّمة!‬
‫أرجوك لا‬
‫أنت، سأقتلك، أيتها العظاية البلهاء!‬
‫سأخنقك!‬
‫طائر كبير، طائر كبير!‬
‫انتظر، عد إلى هنا، كنت أمزح!‬
‫- نحن صديقان, لا؟‬
‫-لا أعرفك!‬
‫- عظايات، ضفادع‬
‫-جد مخبأك الخاص!‬
‫-نحن شبه قريبين!‬
‫-لا مكان في النزل!‬
‫-تنح جانبا!‬
‫-لست صديقي!‬
‫سأدعك تقبّل أختي!‬
‫يا ابن...‬
‫أين أصدقاؤك الآن يا رفيقي؟‬
‫انزع سلامياتك اللّزجة المكفّفة عن جزمتي!‬
‫عذرا‬
‫سلاحي مصوّب عليك أيها الغريب، انهض ببطء‬
‫ما لم ترد تمضية اليوم في إعادة تركيب وجهك!‬
‫- لا سيدتي, لا أريد ذلك‬
‫- من أنت؟‬
‫- من أنا؟‬
‫-أنا اطرح الاسئلة هنا!‬
‫بلدتنا تصاب بالجفاف‬
‫هناك من يرمي الماء في الصحراء!‬
‫هذا لغز كبير لكنني سأعرف دورك في ذلك‬
‫- دوري؟‬
‫- ما شأنك في المسألة؟‬
‫يسرّني أنك سألتني‬
‫أنتج مسرحيتين من فصل واحد، لغزا‬
‫ومسرحية موسيقية‬
‫ألّفت الكلمات وأعمل على اللحن حاليا‬
‫إنه فيلم عن الغرب‬
‫تناول قرد بسكويتا وأمه مجرد ساقطة‬
‫ستأتي من خلف الجبال تحت المطر!‬
‫لست من هذه الأرجاء، صحيح؟‬
‫ما زلت أعمل على ذلك‬
‫إذا ما اسمك؟‬
‫- "فاصوليا"‬
‫- يا له من اسم غريب‬
‫ماذا تريد؟ كان أبي يحب الفاصوليا المحمّصة‬
‫أنت محظوظة لأنه لم يكن يحب الهليون‬
‫ماذا تقول؟‬
‫أحب الصلصة الحرّيفة لكنني لا أظن أن أي ولد‬
‫سيحب هذا الاسم‬
‫كان أبي رجلا عظيما، حتى إن كان يحب الخضار‬
‫- حرّيفة‬
‫- إنك تأكل رماده‬
‫تحملين رفاته؟‬
‫لا، الرماد، كان يحب التدخين، لم يجدوا جثته‬
‫أنا واثق أنه كانت لديه أسبابه‬
‫- إلام تلمح؟‬
‫- لا شيء‬
‫لم يقترب أبي قط من هذا المنجم‬
‫كان صاحيا منذ أكثر من شهر!‬
‫أي تلميح إلى أنه قد يتخلى عن مسؤولياته كأب‬
‫في لحظة حاسمة من فترة بلوغي هي إهانة‬
‫آنسة "فاصوليا"؟‬
‫آنسة "فاصوليا"؟ مرحبا؟‬
‫مرحبا؟‬
‫وما لم يعيدوه سليما معافى، لن أبيع مزرعتي‬
‫- ماذا تفعلين؟‬
‫- ماذا تفعل؟‬
‫- أنا؟‬
‫- أنت تحضنني‬
‫- كنت مجمّدة‬
‫- لم أكن كذلك‬
‫بلى، توقفت عن الكلام‬
‫إنها آلية دفاع، تملكها عظايات كثيرة‬
‫تبتكرين ذلك‬
‫هل تنوي الموت هنا أو نجول في البلدة؟‬
‫لا، أجل، لا، بلى من فضلك، شكرا، عذرا‬
‫إنه يوم الأربعاء، ويوم الأربعاء ننطلق‬
‫إذا، من أنت فعلا؟‬
‫أنا رجل له صفات عدة، اسمي كممثّل، ككاتب‬
‫كان لدي اسم مستعار لكنني طلبت تغييره شرعا‬
‫إذا الغريب الذي يبحث عن الرفقة‬
‫وجد المرأة كما حوريات الزمن الغابر‬
‫تجذبه إلى موته المحتوم‬
‫لدي نظام لاسلكي، أنا من الرجال القلائل‬
‫الذين يملكون اسم فتاة‬
‫حسنا، ها نحن‬
‫حسنا‬
‫اقدّر ذلك آنسة "فاصوليا" وإن أمكنني...‬
‫هيا!‬
‫حسنا إذا!‬
‫أراك لاحقا، "فاصوليا"‬
‫اهلا بكم في "القذارة"‬
‫سترحل "جيم"؟‬
‫بذلنا قصارى جهدنا، كان علينا البيع‬
‫لا يمكننا زراعة المحصول بدون ماء‬
‫وداعا!‬
‫ما هذا؟‬
‫ما سبب ذلك؟‬
‫شكلك غريب‬
‫حقا؟ أنت أيضا غريبة الشكل‬
‫- هذا قميص غريب‬
‫- هذا فستان غريب‬
‫-عيناك غريبتان!‬
‫-وجهك غريب!‬
‫أنت غريب، والغرباء لا يدومون طويلا هنا‬
‫هذه الفاصوليا لك، "فاصوليا"‬
‫أريد المزيد من العلف أيضا، "ويلي"‬
‫تدينين لي بثلاثة أرباع أصلا‬
‫لا يمكنني إقراضك أكثر‬
‫عند الظهيرة أعطيك ما أدين لك به‬
‫لا تفهمين، في المصرف‬
‫أوقف السيد "ميريماك" جميع القروض‬
‫مرحبا "فاصوليا"!‬
‫هل تعرفين هذا الشاب؟‬
‫مرحبا "فاصوليا"، آنسة "فاصوليا"!‬
‫لا‬
‫فاصوليا!‬
‫تموّه، حسنا، تموّه‬
‫حانة‬
‫أريد كوب ماء‬
‫يريد كوب ماء!‬
‫ليكن مزدوجا!‬
‫أعطه المبصقة!‬
‫عصير الصبير، هذا ما لدينا‬
‫أنت، يا كوب الفاكهة‬
‫أنت بعيد عن ديارك، لا؟‬
‫من أنت بالتحديد؟‬
‫من أنا؟‬
‫قد أكون أيا كان‬
‫ما الخطب؟ تفتقد صدر أمك؟‬
‫في الواقع، أجل‬
‫لكن ليس بقدر ما أفتقد طعام ابيك!‬
‫ذكّرني بالتحديد من أين تأتي؟‬
‫أنا؟ أنا من الغرب‬
‫هناك، خلف الأفق، ما بعد الشمس الغاربة‬
‫الغرب الأقصى‬
‫هذا صحيح يا رجال‬
‫في دياري نقتل رجلا قبل الفطور لنفتح الشهية‬
‫ثم نرش عليه الملح والبهار‬
‫ونقليه بالزبدة ثم نأكله‬
‫- تأكلونه؟‬
‫-هذا ما قلته!‬
‫رأيت أشياء تفقد الإنسان سيطرته‬
‫على وظائف غدده!‬
‫نمضي ٣ أيام في جيفة جواد نتغذى من سوائلنا‬
‫وهذا أمر يغيّر الإنسان، أجل‬
‫كان لدي بعض الأصوص في هذه اللعبة يا سادة‬
‫تماما كما أحبه‬
‫إذا يا صديقي القارض، لست من هذه الانحاء‬
‫يمكنكم القول إنني من حيث الفوضى عارمة‬
‫والجلبة الجهنمية بانتظار من يثيرها‬
‫يمكن القول إنني من هذا الجحيم‬
‫اسمي...‬
‫"رانغو"‬
‫أنت الذي قتل الإخوة "جنكنز"؟‬
‫أجل، قتلتهم برصاصة واحدة‬
‫ماتوا أشد ميتة‬
‫السبعة؟‬
‫هذا صحيح‬
‫السبعة جميعا‬
‫كيف فعلت ذلك بالتحديد سيد "رانغو"؟‬
‫يسرّني أنك سألتني‬
‫وسيفرحني إخباركم لكن عليكم الإصغاء!‬
‫إذ هنا يغدو الأمر‬
‫معقّدا‬
‫بهذا تقفلين حسابك، بلعتان وجرعة‬
‫انزع يديك "مورديخاي"، هذا ما بقي‬
‫من تعليمك الجامعي!‬
‫لا خيار آخر لدي، "فاصوليا"‬
‫إنها أوقات صعبة، لا يمكننا منح القروض‬
‫لكنه مصرف، هنا تحتفظون بالماء‬
‫فاصوليا، كنت أشبه بنسيبتي منذ لم يسقط‬
‫أبوك ثملا في منجم‬
‫حاولت حمايتك وغيرك من حقائق محدّدة‬
‫لكن... حسنا...‬
‫سيد "ميريماك"؟‬
‫سيد "ميريماك"!‬
‫أنت بخير؟‬
‫فاصوليا، سأريك شيئا‬
‫-هذا كل ما بقي!‬
‫-وهذا الاحتياط!‬
‫لا أعلم إن لاحظت لكن ما عاد الناس يتركون‬
‫الودائع يوم الأربعاء‬
‫سيد "ميريماك"، إن لم أحصل على الماء‬
‫أخسر مزرعتي‬
‫وتقول إنه كل ما بقي؟ هذا مناف للمنطق، اسمع‬
‫هناك من يرمي الماء في الصحراء‬
‫رأيت ذلك بأم عيني‬
‫الماء في الصحراء؟‬
‫هل حصل ذلك خلال... لحظاتك المميزة؟‬
‫لا‬
‫يمكننا جميعا أن نحلم، لكن هذا هو الواقع‬
‫لم تخالين الكثيرين يبيعون؟‬
‫يعجزون عن كسب عيشهم‬
‫حسنا، ماذا يفترض بي أن أفعل؟‬
‫افترض أنه بوسعنا أن نكلّم العمدة‬
‫- سمعت أنه يساعد الناس‬
‫- العمدة؟‬
‫قد يكون أملنا الوحيد‬
‫أصابت الرصاصة مجرفة وارتدّت على الثالث‬
‫ثم انهار السقف‬
‫فأشعل حاوية المادة المخمّرة‬
‫فأدّى إلى تبخّر جسمه تاركا تمثالا من فحم‬
‫وصراخا حادّا‬
‫مهلا، هؤلاء ستة فقط، ماذا عن السابع؟‬
‫السابع؟‬
‫تبّا، مات إثر إصابته بالتهاب‬
‫-سبعة رجال!‬
‫-رصاصة واحدة!‬
‫وزّعوا الشراب للجميع!‬
‫ارقص لي "سود باستر"!‬
‫أجل، ارقص كالدجاجة، ارقص!‬
‫هل أنت أصم يا رجل؟ إن لم تدفع الرهن‬
‫تخسر الأرض‬
‫هذا قانون العقارات‬
‫شيء مقابل آخر!‬
‫إن رأيت وجهك في هذه البلدة مجددا‬
‫سأقطّعه إربا وأستعمله لمسح ما لن أسمّيه‬
‫انتبه الى المنقار‬
‫ولا تعد مجددا!‬
‫بم تحملقون جميعا؟‬
‫باد بيل أريد أن أقول لك شيئا!‬
‫ما هو؟‬
‫هل تعرف من هذا "بيل"؟ إنه "رانغو"!‬
‫لا يخشاك، لا يخشى أيا منكم‬
‫فقد قتل الأخوة "جنكنز"‬
‫- برصاصة واحدة‬
‫-السبعة معا!‬
‫هل هذا صحيح؟‬
‫دعني أطفئها قبل ان...‬
‫أعلم، هاك‬
‫سأتولى إطفاءها‬
‫هاك، هذا أفضل‬
‫وقت مستقطع، وقت مستقطع، لحظة‬
‫اسمعوني!‬
‫سأعطيكم فرصة أخيرة لتعيدوا التفكير!‬
‫وإن كنتم لا تريدون إعادة التفكير‬
‫قد أفكر في إعادة التفكير بالوضع بنفسي‬
‫هذا ما أقصده‬
‫اسمعوا، لن تبقى الأمور على حالها‬
‫بعد مجيء "رانغو" إلى البلدة‬
‫ستكون هناك قواعد جديدة!‬
‫أريد تلميع حذائي كل صباح، قهوة ساخنة وكعكة‬
‫مهما فعلتم، لا تنظروا مباشرة في عيني‬
‫-إنه "رانغو"‬
‫- ما الذي يفعله؟‬
‫لا يخشى أحدا، وهو يؤنّبهم بقساوة!‬
‫حين ترونني قادما، تنحوا جانبا‬
‫خطواتي كبيرة ولا أريدكم أن تلطّخوا جزمتي‬
‫بإفرازات أجسامكم!‬
‫طبعا، لا داعي لاستعمال العنف ما دمنا‬
‫متعاضدين ونعمل كفريق واحد‬
‫أريدكم جميعا أن تخرجوا وتقفوا في الصف‬
‫بينما آخذ استراحتي!‬
‫ماذا يفعل الآن؟‬
‫الثانية على ما أظن‬
‫مشغول‬
‫ما من مشكلة‬
‫انظروا هنا!‬
‫انظروا إليه!‬
‫يطارد ذلك الصقر!‬
‫لقّنه درسا، "رانغو"!‬
‫- هل رأيتم ذلك؟‬
‫-قتل ذلك الشيء!‬
‫ما رأيك "دوك"؟‬
‫مات هذا الصقر!‬
‫رائع، فلنطهه في الحال‬
‫قتله برصاصة واحدة!‬
‫كما قال تماما!‬
‫آن الآوان ليأتينا بطل إلى هنا‬
‫بطل ليس ممدّدا في تابوت‬
‫آن الأوان ليلتقي بالعمدة‬
‫هل سمعت ذلك "رانغو" ستلتقي بالعمدة!‬
‫تحية إلى "رانغو"‬
‫وهكذا العظاية الغريبة‬
‫تنعمت بتملّق أصدقائها الجدد‬
‫وغرقت أكثر فأكثر في حبكة خداعها‬
‫متى سيموت؟‬
‫قريبا يا صديقي، قريبا‬
‫أرضي ليست للبيع!‬
‫جئت إلى هنا لإنقاذ أرضي وليس لبيعها!‬
‫أنا واثق أنه يسعنا تدبر شيء إن كلّمته فقط!‬
‫فاصوليا! أين تذهبين؟‬
‫سيراك العمدة الآن‬
‫ماء سيد "رانغو"، ماء‬
‫بدونها، لا يبقى سوى الغبار والعفن‬
‫لكن بالماء...‬
‫لدينا الحياة‬
‫انظر اليهم، توّاقون جدا للعيش‬
‫بحيث يتبعونها إلى أي مكان‬
‫إنه قانون الصحراء الذي لا يتغيّر‬
‫تحكّم بالماء فتتحكم بكل شيء‬
‫هذا من احتياطي الشخصي‬
‫ماء مطرية معتّقة من الفيضان الكبير‬
‫ليس فيضان "نوح"، بحق السماء لست عجوزا‬
‫إلى هذا الحد‬
‫أظن أن للسلطة امتيازاتها‬
‫أحسنت القول بني‬
‫لكن هذه الامتيازات تأتي مرفقة بمسؤوليات‬
‫تبّا، كنت عمدة هنا قبل مجيء "القذارة"!‬
‫وقد أكون مجرد سلحفاة عجوز عاطفية‬
‫لكنني أظن أن هذه البلدة لها مستقبل‬
‫وآمل أن تشكّل جزءا منه‬
‫نخب "القذارة"!‬
‫نخب "القذارة"‬
‫هل تراهم سيد "رانغو"؟ أصدقائي وجيراني كافة‬
‫الحياة شاقة هنا، شاقة جدا‬
‫هل تعرف كيف يتدبّرون أمورهم كل يوم؟ يؤمنون‬
‫يؤمنون أن الأمور ستتحسّن‬
‫يؤمنون أن الماء ستأتي‬
‫يؤمنون أنه على الرغم من كل شيء سيكون الغد‬
‫أفضل من اليوم‬
‫يجدر بالناس أن يؤمنوا بشيء ما‬
‫حاليا...‬
‫يؤمنون بك‬
‫خذها سيد "رانغو"‬
‫قدرك على وشك أن يتحقّق‬
‫على الناس أن يؤمنوا بشيء ما‬
‫هذا مناف للمنطق‬
‫البلدة في جفاف والعمدة هو الوحيد‬
‫غير المتأثّر بذلك‬
‫ألا يبدو لك ذلك مريبا بعض الشيء؟‬
‫ماذا عن الماء التي رأيتها في الصحراء؟‬
‫حسنا، لا داعي لإثارة القلق‬
‫سأتقصّى بشأن العمدة‬
‫لكن إن كنت تشعرين حقا بوجود مؤامرة ما‬
‫أقترح عليك أن تتوجهي إلى الشريف الجديد‬
‫سيكون ذلك جيدا، انتبه لتلك الإبرة‬
‫ليس ضيقا جدا، أريد ترك فسحة للجعدات!‬
‫على مهلك أيها النمر‬
‫ألديك كمّان فرنسيان مع هذا؟‬
‫أرجو المعذرة أيها الشريف‬
‫فاصوليا، أعجبك اللباس الجديد؟ لدي قبعة‬
‫كبيرة مخفّضة الى ١٥‬
‫- هذا جيد‬
‫-هل تعرفت ب"أنجيليك"؟‬
‫-مرحبا "فاصوليا"‬
‫-مرحبا "أنجيليك"‬
‫- سافلة‬
‫- حقيرة‬
‫- لعوب‬
‫- أرجو المعذرة سيد "رانغو"‬
‫سأزيل ذلك التعبير اللعين عن وجهك!‬
‫كنت أفكر وحسب...‬
‫هل تريد توقيعي؟ امسك هذا‬
‫ليست زيارة اجتماعية‬
‫توجد رصاصة فيه‬
‫أعرف بشأن الحفلة بعد ظهر اليوم‬
‫طلبت بعض الملابس الجميلة‬
‫-سيد "رانغو"‬
‫- أنت أيضا؟‬
‫أريدك ان...‬
‫فاصوليا، أراهن أنك فاتنة إن بذلت جهدا‬
‫ابق في المدرسة، كل الخضار وأحرق كل شيء‬
‫عدا "شيكسبير"‬
‫شريف "رانغو"!‬
‫إن كان هذا اسمك الحقيقي‬
‫أحاول إنقاذ مزرعة أبي التي يوشك الجفاف‬
‫على إتلافها‬
‫بينما تغازل هذه الحقيرة‬
‫هذا مؤسف فعلا‬
‫يا لها من تافهة بلهاء‬
‫لم تفعل ذلك؟‬
‫- هذا رد فعل انعكاسي للنجاة‬
‫- مفتاحها مكسور‬
‫حسنا، هذا مزعج‬
‫ليس طفحا جلديا، إنها علامة خلقية‬
‫فعلت ذلك مجددا، صحيح؟‬
‫ماذا فعلت؟‬
‫دعني أطرح عليك سؤالا‬
‫هل ذكر لك أحد هنا ما حل بآخر شريف لدينا؟‬
‫عذرا لكن هل لي أن أطلب... عذرا، هل أطلب...‬
‫آخر شريف، أرجو المعذرة، أين يذهب الجميع؟‬
‫ماذا حصل بالتحديد...؟‬
‫طوال اليوم‬
‫واجهت الأرض القاحلة‬
‫بدون تذوّق طعم الماء‬
‫ماء عذبة‬
‫دان العجوز وانا...‬
‫حلقانا جافان ومؤلمان‬
‫وروحانا تبكيان...‬
‫توقا للماء‬
‫آسف جدا، آسف جدا‬
‫عذبة...‬
‫ماء صافية‬
‫هذه رقصة مذهلة، ما زلت تتمرن على خطواتك‬
‫إذا يعتبر هذا سلوك متمدّن؟‬
‫كل أربعاء، كالساعة‬
‫أنت قتلت عصفورا‬
‫في الواقع، اجل‬
‫عصفور ميت، ستأتي الأفعى‬
‫- أفعى؟‬
‫-يقصد المجلجلة "جايك"، سيد "رانغو"‬
‫لم تأت قط إلى البلدة لأن الصقر أخافها‬
‫قد تأتي الآن‬
‫- هل لي بأخذ جزمتك بعد موتك؟‬
‫-لا!‬
‫ولا مشكلة لدي مع هذه المجلجلة "جايك"‬
‫هذا ما قاله "آموس"‬
‫آموس؟‬
‫الشريف "عاموس"‬
‫من الخميس إلى السبت - يرقد بسلام‬
‫ألديك حشوات ضرس ذهبية؟‬
‫يا سكان بلدة "القذارة"‬
‫أهلا بكم في يوم التحرير الكبير، هللويا‬
‫هللويا!‬
‫يا مساعدي الكاهن، أعدّوا الحنفية!‬
‫لدينا وافد جديد بيننا اليوم، يا أصدقائي‬
‫رجل أعتقد أنه بغنى عن التعريف‬
‫نظرا لدخوله الجريء إلى مجتمعنا‬
‫سيد "رانغو"، هلا تتقدّم؟‬
‫حان الوقت يا أصدقائي، الوقت الذي تنبؤون به‬
‫هللويا!‬
‫الوقت المقدّس!‬
‫وقت القدر!‬
‫هللويا!‬
‫وقت التحرير!‬
‫إنها لحظة...‬
‫الرطوبة!‬
‫-هو المخطئ!‬
‫-إنه القادم الجديد!‬
‫-أحرقوه!‬
‫-إنه ساحر!‬
‫سآخذ جزمته!‬
‫يا أصدقائي، يا أصدقائي، هدّئوا من روعكم‬
‫ستحين أزمنة صعبة من الآن فصاعدا‬
‫علينا القيام بتضحيات‬
‫لكن إن أمكنني المساعدة، اعلموا أن بابي...‬
‫توقفوا، توقفوا!‬
‫كل هذه المسألة تبدو لي مريبة‬
‫أولا، فرغ المصرف والآن هذه الحنفيّة؟‬
‫فرغ المصرف؟‬
‫- ماذا؟‬
‫-قالت إن الماء نفد من المصرف!‬
‫هذا كل ما لدينا، لا يمكننا إعطاؤه كله!‬
‫أقفل حساب الترطيب الخاص بي!‬
‫لن أقبل بهذا العصيان المدني في بلدتي‬
‫شكرا جزيلا‬
‫الحمد لله أيها الشريف‬
‫كانت الأمور قد خرجت عن السيطرة‬
‫ادخلوا‬
‫دعوني أنظر الى مصدر الامتعاض الاجتماعي‬
‫الرحمة‬
‫اسمعوا، كنت أفكر‬
‫وأظنني وجدت حلا‬
‫تواجهون مشكلة مياه!‬
‫انتبهوا، أحاول تبيان قصدي‬
‫لنفترض أن هذا الفتى يريد شرب الماء، بلعة‬
‫ما من مشكلة، صحيح؟‬
‫وأنت!‬
‫أنت ظمآن كما الأرنب البرّي في شهر تموز‬
‫لذا تقترب وتتناول جرعة مزدوجة!‬
‫اصبروا قليلا‬
‫ماذا يحصل برأيكم آنذاك؟ سنشرب جميعا!‬
‫وسرعان ما تنفد المياه، وأين يودي بنا ذلك؟‬
‫سنصاب بالعطش‬
‫بالعطش الشديد‬
‫ونتشاجر في ما بيننا كالحيوانات المسعورة!‬
‫اسمعوا، لدينا ماء تكفي ستة أيام‬
‫لدينا خمسة أيام‬
‫ما دام لدينا الماء، لدينا بلدة‬
‫شريف "رانغو" على حق‬
‫ما دامت لدينا هذه الماء، لدينا أمل‬
‫ثقوا بكلامي‬
‫بدءا من الآن، سيكون شغلي الشاغل‬
‫حماية مصدرنا الطبيعي الغالي‬
‫لا أحد... سيتقاتل مع "رانغو"‬
‫مساء الخير سيداتي‬
‫مساء الخير أيها الشريف‬
‫ولا تعد إلى هنا!‬
‫انتبه "غوردي"، عد وافرض نفسك‬
‫سترى أن سكان هذه المدينة مضيافون جدا‬
‫شكرا أيها الشريف‬
‫ماذا؟ ليس أنت مجددا!‬
‫أقرّ بخطئي‬
‫- هذا ليس المصرف‬
‫-قلت لك "جديديا"!‬
‫لا تتحركا!‬
‫- من هذا؟‬
‫-الشريف!‬
‫ارفعا أيديكما حيث أراها!‬
‫كما شككت تماما‬
‫تنقيب بدون معدات مجازة، لا تتحركا‬
‫تنقيب؟‬
‫لنر، مجرفة، معول، "بينادريل"، لوفة‬
‫مقبّلات متنوعة، كتب أحجيات...‬
‫وستحتاجان إلى رخصة‬
‫- لوفة‬
‫-"إزيكيال"، "جديديا"!‬
‫ماذا يحصل بحق السماء؟‬
‫خضعت لاستئصال أورام أذكى منكما الاثنين!‬
‫تبّا، هذا ليس المصرف!‬
‫أبي، الشريف هنا يساعدنا‬
‫يعطينا رخصة للتنقيب‬
‫هذا صحيح سيدي، أنجز واجبي وحسب‬
‫الشرطي الوحيد في جولته، يرصد بحذر الجريمة‬
‫هل هو فعلا كما يبدو لي؟‬
‫حسنا شريف، إن أردنا إصابة العرق الرئيس‬
‫كوننا منقّبين وما إلى ذلك‬
‫أين نودع الدخل المذكور؟‬
‫في بلدة "القذارة"، لدينا أفضل مؤسسة مالية‬
‫في هذا الجزء من نهر "ميسوري"‬
‫بنك القدارة‬
‫محمي في الصباح، الظهر والمساء من قبلي‬
‫شكرا‬
‫سرق المصرف، سرق المصرف!‬
‫يا إلهي، سرق المصرف!‬
‫ماذا يجري؟‬
‫اختفت، اختفت الماء!‬
‫يقول إن المصرف سرق!‬
‫د. "ماركس" إنني أشتعل، ضمّني!‬
‫سرق المصرف، البلدة جافة، "سنموت من العطش"‬
‫يبكي الشعب‬
‫وعد بحماية السرداب، اختفت الماء، هذا خطؤه‬
‫تراجعوا، أخلوا المنطقة، هذا مسرح جريمة‬
‫انزعوا البصمات، تأكدوا من الألياف‬
‫أجروا مسحا للحمض النووي‬
‫أريد عيّنة بول من الجميع‬
‫واجلبوا لي قهوة بالحليب‬
‫ولا تمزجوا الاثنين‬
‫ما هذا؟‬
‫إذن بالتنقيب‬
‫سآخذ هذا، إثبات مادي‬
‫ماذا نفعل الآن؟‬
‫- نحتاج إلى المياه‬
‫-سنموت جميعا!‬
‫يا أصدقائي، نعرف جميعا ما علينا فعله الآن‬
‫هذا صحيح، نعرف ما علينا فعله الآن‬
‫- وهو...؟‬
‫- تشكيل فرقة معاونين‬
‫تشكيل أبوسوم!‬
‫فرقة‬
‫سنقوم بذلك بشكل منظّم‬
‫أولا، هل يجيد أحدكم استعمال سلاح ناري؟‬
‫جيد‬
‫ماذا نفعل الآن؟‬
‫حاليا... ننطلق‬
‫أين نذهب؟!‬
‫ماذا؟!‬
‫لون ستار‬
‫كنائبي، أنت مسؤول عن تقصّي الأشرار‬
‫باستعمال براعتك المتمرّسة، لا أقصد الإهانة‬
‫أين ذهبوا؟ هل تريد تنشّق الهواء أو التواصل‬
‫مع جاموس؟‬
‫أنت بارع‬
‫أعتمد عليك "سبونز"‬
‫لديك بعض آثار التبغ على لحيتك‬
‫يسرّني جدا وجود طبيب معي، "دوك"‬
‫على الزواحف التضامن مع بعضها، صحيح أخي؟‬
‫أنا برمائي‬
‫لا داعي للخجل بذلك‬
‫أنت واثق أنك مخوّل للعمل، أيها الجندي؟‬
‫لديك شيء في عينك‬
‫هذا؟ التهاب باطن الجفن سيدي، إنه وراثي‬
‫يسرّني أن أعلم أنه ليس معديا‬
‫مهلا قليلا، فرقة المعاونين ليست مكانا...‬
‫لا عليك‬
‫مهلا يا أختاه‬
‫على أحدهم أن يحرس البلدة بغيابي‬
‫أيمكنني إطلاق النار على أحد في احشائه؟‬
‫لنؤجّل ذلك‬
‫شريف، ستعيد المياه، أليس كذلك؟‬
‫اعتمدي علي يا أختاه‬
‫- من أية ناحية شريف؟‬
‫- توجد أنفاق في كل مكان‬
‫إنها تملأ البلدة برمّتها‬
‫كيف عثروا على المصرف بأية حال؟‬
‫أيها السادة، لنركّز على مهمّتنا‬
‫شريف، من هذه الناحية!‬
‫- انظروا إلى هذه‬
‫- كأنني أرى وجه القدير‬
‫آمين يا أخي‬
‫اذكر حين كانت تتدفق كل أربعاء‬
‫كانت أياما جميلة‬
‫لا بد من وجود سبب جعلها تكف عن التدفق‬
‫مهما كان السبب، هناك شيء يتحكم بهذه الماء‬
‫ما قولك أيها الشريف؟‬
‫من الواضح أن السارقين أتوا من هذا الاتجاه‬
‫لنقتف المصدر الهيدروليكي‬
‫ونعتقل مرتكبي هذا اللغز‬
‫- ماذا قال؟‬
‫- أظنه قال أن نتبع الانابيب‬
‫- قال أن تتبعوا الأنابيب‬
‫- اتبعوا الانابيب‬
‫مهما فعلتم، لا تنظروا إلى الأسفل‬
‫- ما هذا المكان؟‬
‫- إنها طبقة جوفية‬
‫ما معنى الطبقة الجوفية؟‬
‫إنها مصدر للماء‬
‫حسنا، إنها فارغة الآن‬
‫إنه كبير جدا‬
‫- نهاية الطريق‬
‫- لا يذهب أكثر من ذلك‬
‫هناك أحد أو شيء يعبث بمياهنا‬
‫وهذا الأنبوب له علاقة بذلك‬
‫خلتنا نتعقّب سارقي المصارف!‬
‫نختبر تغييرا بارزا في نموذج التفكير‬
‫اصمت وإلا غيّرت ملامح وجهك‬
‫هيا حاول ذلك‬
‫اصمتوا أيها المتوحشون، تفسدون علي تأمّلي‬
‫وجدتها، أطفئوا مشاعلكم‬
‫بالتأكيد‬
‫أحسنت التفكير يا صديقي‬
‫- ابدؤوا بالتسلّق‬
‫-أبعد رجلك عن وجهي!‬
‫لا بأس بذلك، "فاصوليا"؟‬
‫استمر في التفكير بهذا الشكل وستحترق قبعتك‬
‫حين تتدفق الأفكار، أنت...‬
‫حار، حار، احترق‬
‫المساكين، أرادوا بعض الماء وحسب‬
‫الصبير يموت من العطش، هذا لا ينبىء بالخير‬
‫-انظروا ماذا وجدت!‬
‫- ما هذه؟‬
‫-رأيتها اولا!‬
‫-إنها لي!‬
‫أعطني إياها!‬
‫إنها فارغة بأية حال‬
‫كنت واثقا من ذلك‬
‫أين وجدتها؟‬
‫شريف، عليك رؤية هذا!‬
‫إنه السيد "ميريماك" من المصرف‬
‫ماذا يفعل هنا؟‬
‫- تراجعوا‬
‫- دعوني أرى‬
‫يبدو أن السفلة أطلقوا عليه النار من الخلف‬
‫لا، لم يطلق النار على هذا الرجل، بل غرق!‬
‫- غرق؟‬
‫- وسط الصحراء?‬
‫يا لها من طريقة للموت‬
‫لمن آثار الحذاء هذه؟‬
‫هذا مثير للاهتمام، ما زالت الأرض رطبة‬
‫أفترض أنه يجدر بنا دفنه‬
‫لا أعلم، على الطيور أن تأكل أيضا‬
‫دائرة الحياة!‬
‫ماذا يفعل هذا الهندي الحقير؟‬
‫أرى أنك تستشير الأرواح‬
‫لا، أطرح ريشي وحسب، أي أنني جاهز للتزاوج‬
‫سأتذكر ذلك‬
‫ثمرة الصبّير‬
‫أجل، ثمرة الصبّير القديمة‬
‫أظن أنكم تستعملونها لتنكيه أطباقكم المحلية‬
‫وكمسهّل إمعاء طبيعي‬
‫وجدت الأثر‬
‫٣ رجال متجهون غربا، أحدهم أعمى والآخر‬
‫لديه بروستات ملتهبة ويركب سرجا جانبيا‬
‫- ماذا قال؟‬
‫- يركبون سرجا جانبيا‬
‫- نحن نهمس‬
‫- ماذا قال؟‬
‫أحدهم لديه صمّام مصاب‬
‫من منكم يريد الخضوع لفحص طبي؟‬
‫هذا محرج‬
‫ماذا سنفعل الآن؟‬
‫الآن... ننطلق!‬
‫أي أننا سنركب الجواد، في هذه اللحظة‬
‫الخطمي تذكّرني بالتخييم مع أبي‬
‫كنت آكل منها طوال الليل‬
‫بالطبع كان يجبرني على بصقها من أجل الفطور‬
‫ذات مرة، بصقت كلبا مرقّطا كاملا‬
‫ليس بشيء، بصقت قبيلة كاملة من الأقزام‬
‫بدؤوا يرمقونني بنظرات غريبة‬
‫أذكرهم، كانوا ودّيين جدا‬
‫ذات مرة، وجدت عمودا فقريا بشريا في برازي‬
‫عليك أن تخضع للمعاينة الطبية‬
‫مرّري الفاصوليا، "فاصوليا"‬
‫- شريف؟‬
‫- لا شكرا‬
‫سيد "رانغو"؟ هلا تخبرنا عن روح الغرب؟‬
‫- أجل، أخبرنا‬
‫- هل صحيح ما يقال؟‬
‫أجل، روح الغرب!‬
‫المثال الذي لا يمكن بلوغه أبدا‬
‫يقال إنها تتنقل في عربة مرمرية‬
‫مع حرّاس من ذهب‬
‫لكنها لا تظهر إلا للذين خاضوا سعيا بطوليا!‬
‫ومن تمكنوا من العبور‬
‫إلى الطرف الآخر‬
‫أي طرف آخر؟‬
‫إنها استعارة‬
‫عيني!‬
‫ستشفى تماما‬
‫شريف؟ ماذا ستفعل بـ"جايك" الأفعى المجلجلة؟‬
‫ماذا؟ أين؟‬
‫عذرا، تسري شائعة أنك واجهتها مرة او اثنتين‬
‫أجل‬
‫جايك، تعني أخي‬
‫-أخوك؟‬
‫-هذا ما قلته!‬
‫لكنها أفعى وأنت عظاية‬
‫كانت لأمي حياة اجتماعية ناشطة‬
‫هل عضّتك يوما؟‬
‫بالطبع، انظر، هيا يمكنك لمسها‬
‫هذا مثير للاهتمام، أن تكون لديك سرّة‬
‫لدي مناعة على سمّها، أضعه في قهوتي‬
‫ليصبح مذاقه حادّا‬
‫هل تخاف من الصقور وحسب؟‬
‫إنها ما يسمونها مفترسها الطبيعي‬
‫التحدث عن تلك الأفعى الشيطانية يثير توتري‬
‫لن أنام هذا المساء، لا سيدي‬
‫لا تقلق، غدا سنجد الماء ونعود عودة الأبطال‬
‫يا أصدقائي، قبل أن نخلد إلى الفراش‬
‫أريدكم ان ترفعوا أيديكم وتصلّوا لروح الغرب‬
‫إنها فكرة جيدة‬
‫يا روح الغرب، لم أتوجه اليك دائما باحترام‬
‫لكن هذا المساء‬
‫اود شكرك على إدخال الشريف "رانغو"‬
‫إلى حياتنا‬
‫حياتنا شاقة‬
‫أحيانا، لا أعلم كيف سننجو‬
‫لكن بشكل او بآخر، يجعلني الشريف "رانغو"‬
‫أؤمن بذلك‬
‫كنا بحاجة إلى رجل شجاع وأرسلت لنا واحدا‬
‫من الجيد أن نحظى بشخص نؤمن به مجددا‬
‫شكرا يا روح الغرب، آمين‬
‫آمين‬
‫أتفقّد وحسب‬
‫- الطقس بارد قليلا هذا المساء‬
‫- شكرا‬
‫هل تشعرين أحيانا أن هذه الاشياء تنظر اليك؟‬
‫هذا خنجر إسباني لكننا نسمّيه الصبير السائر‬
‫سائر؟‬
‫تحكي الأسطورة أنها تسير عبر الصحراء‬
‫بحثا عن الماء‬
‫في صغري، كنت أبقى مستيقظة حتى ساعة متأخرة‬
‫لأرى إن كانت تتحرك‬
‫كنت أعتقد أنني إن تبعتها، سترشدني‬
‫إلى مكان مذهل‬
‫مكان فيه ما يكفي من الماء للجميع‬
‫راقبتها ليلة تلو الأخرى ولم أرها قط تتحرك‬
‫لكنك ما زلت تراقبينها‬
‫من قد لا يرغب في العثور على مكان مذهل؟‬
‫سنجد الماء "فاصوليا"، أعدك بذلك‬
‫هذا صوت وحيد جدا‬
‫هل تشعر أحيانا بالوحدة؟‬
‫أحيانا‬
‫لا أتخيّل ذلك، أنت ساحر والجميع يعشقك‬
‫لم يسهل علي قط كسب الأصدقاء‬
‫نحن منعزلون جدا في المزرعة‬
‫كأننا محجوزون في علبة‬
‫لا نرى الكثير من الأشخاص‬
‫أعجز عن تخيّل ذلك‬
‫هل من شخص مميّز في حياتك "رانغو"؟‬
‫كان هناك أحد لكنها فقدت صوابها‬
‫حياتي خطيرة جدا لهذه الأمور‬
‫الحياة وحيدة في البرية‬
‫أتنقل بين البراري وما إلى ذلك‬
‫فاصوليا؟‬
‫سأسلخك حيّا يا فتى، سأقضي عليك‬
‫كأنك ابن زوجتي‬
‫إنهم عصبيون جدا، لا؟‬
‫العائلة مفكّكة وبحاجة إلى علاج‬
‫ما الذي يأتي صوبنا؟‬
‫إنها الماء‬
‫لدي خطة ولكل واحد منكم دور يلعبه فيها‬
‫ماذا أفعل؟‬
‫الدور الأهم، ابق هنا وإن حصل مكروه‬
‫تطلق الإشارة‬
‫فاصوليا، ما مقاس فستانك؟‬
‫-حصل عليها!‬
‫-هللويا!‬
‫-وجد الماء!‬
‫- نجحت في ذلك بني‬
‫في الواقع‬
‫لم لا يمكنك أن تكون ذكيا كأخيك؟‬
‫بشأن الماء، علي إخبارك أمرا‬
‫اصمت، هناك أحد قادم‬
‫أيها السادة الطيبون، طاب يومك ويومك ويومك‬
‫هذه فرقة "مدام لوبون" للممثّلين الجوّالين!‬
‫- ما هذا؟‬
‫- أظنهم ممثّلين‬
‫ممثّلين؟ هذا عمل غير شرعي في ٧ ولايات!‬
‫المسرح جاهز، تستعد الأميرة للانتحار‬
‫أتوق إلى الحب‬
‫في غضون ذلك، الحارس الوحيد يراقب‬
‫اسمعوا، من هناك؟‬
‫هذه الحبكة متوقّعة جدا‬
‫اصمت، هذا جزئي المفضّل‬
‫وصل والدها العجوز وسط معمعة صاخبة‬
‫بعد أن أصابه "كيوبيد"‬
‫رجاء، أفلت ابنتي الجميلة‬
‫ومدّ يديك نحو...‬
‫السطر؟‬
‫مد يديك نحو السماء!‬
‫ما كان ذلك؟‬
‫لا بد أنه مسرح تجريبي‬
‫أنتم محاصرون، أنت وعائلتك ارفعوا أيديكم‬
‫عائلتي برمّتها؟‬
‫البرغل والخضار‬
‫الكعك، دماغ القردة‬
‫عظام مقلية ودماء الأنف‬
‫بيض مخلّل وفطيرة الوحل‬
‫الصالة مليئة‬
‫يبدو أننا وصلنا إلى طريق مسدود‬
‫أعلم أنك لا ترى جميع أعضاء فريقنا‬
‫ما معنى ذلك؟‬
‫إنها الاشارة‬
‫إنها الإشارة، هناك خطب ما!‬
‫إذا... يفترض بشيء أن يحصل؟‬
‫أنا... أستمع لجميع الاقتراحات‬
‫اركضوا!‬
‫اصعدوا الى العربة!‬
‫هل نمارس بعض الرياضة يا أولاد؟‬
‫تروقني رؤيتهم يركضون‬
‫":مايبيل"، صيحي بأعلى صوتك!‬
‫يبدو أننا نجونا!‬
‫كان الجمهور متجاوبا جدا‬
‫أظن أن مخزون الكروموسومات هذا قد جف‬
‫لدينا خفافيش!‬
‫خذي، تولّي القيادة‬
‫يبدو أننا سنحظى بحساء هذا المساء!‬
‫هيا، لنمسك بهم!‬
‫ما هذا؟! لا تطلق النار على الماء!‬
‫جديديا، حان وقت تكتيك الأكورديون!‬
‫حسنا أبي!‬
‫أشعر ببعض العدائية‬
‫هناك ضربة قادمة!‬
‫مرحبا!‬
‫وداعا!‬
‫أمسك هذا الحقير بالحبل!‬
‫أقترح أن نرحل متملّصين!‬
‫أقترح أن تصمتي وتطلقي النار!‬
‫- أين الشريف؟‬
‫-كان لديه ارتباط سابق!‬
‫بوسيفوس هاجمهم فورا!‬
‫هيا، هيا!‬
‫ما كان ذلك؟ اذهب وتحقّق من الأمر!‬
‫إذا؟ هل من مشكلة؟‬
‫يمكنك تسميتها كذلك‬
‫صداع‬
‫هذا كل ما لديك؟!‬
‫لم يكن الأمر مزعجا جدا!‬
‫إليكم الرصاص!‬
‫أمسك هذه‬
‫انزع يديك عني!‬
‫عذرا‬
‫اقفزي!‬
‫هذا مستحيل‬
‫لا يعقل، إنه فارغ‬
‫ما من ماء!‬
‫ما من ماء؟ اذا لم نتقاتل بحق السماء؟‬
‫سيدي، لوّثت ودنّست أساس رزقنا‬
‫أظن أن صاحب الملابس الجميلة هو الشريف‬
‫هو الذي أعطانا إذن التنقيب؟‬
‫ماذا؟‬
‫لا صلة لذلك بالأمر، هذه بلبلة‬
‫أنت وأقرباؤك قيد الاعتقال لسرقة المصرف‬
‫ومقتل مستشارنا المالي الحبيب‬
‫"جوهانس ميريماك الثالث"‬
‫المعروف ب"فلافي جو"‬
‫شريف، لم نقتل أحدا، حفرنا في السرداب‬
‫لكنه كان فارغا‬
‫هناك من قام بسرقته قبلنا‬
‫إذا أين وجدت هذا الإبريق؟‬
‫هذا ما أحاول قوله لك أبي، وجدته في الصحراء‬
‫إذا لم أحضرته إلى هنا بحق السماء؟‬
‫لحظة، تقول إن الإبريق كان فارغا حين وجدته؟‬
‫هذا صحيح‬
‫لا أصدّق ذلك‬
‫-لنشنقهم!‬
‫-علّقوهم!‬
‫من عساه يرمي الماء في الصحراء؟‬
‫لن تكون المرة الأولى‬
‫هذا لغز، كصورة أشعّة للصدر!‬
‫ماذا يجري أيها الشريف؟‬
‫لا أعلم، سأحل هذا اللغز وأكشف عن مكنوناته‬
‫أنت وعائلتك، رافقوني‬
‫إنهم آتون!‬
‫ها هم!‬
‫يبدو أنهم أمسكوا بالسارقين‬
‫أين الماء؟‬
‫لم يكن هناك ماء‬
‫أين يذهب؟‬
‫يذهب لرؤية العمدة‬
‫يجدر به أن يسرّ بذلك‬
‫أحسنت أيها الرئيس!‬
‫هذا مثير للاهتمام‬
‫عذرا على الحذاء سيد "رانغو"‬
‫لكن هناك قاعدة متّبعة في هذه اللعبة‬
‫وأصرّ جدا على تطبيق القواعد‬
‫جيد، إذ عليك الإجابة على بعض الاسئلة‬
‫ولدي قواعدي الخاصة‬
‫لم قد يقدم أحد على رمي الماء في الصحراء؟‬
‫يبدو الأمر ساذجا بعض الشيء، تصديق السارقين‬
‫كما أنك حين تشنقهم، تنجز عملك‬
‫-أحسنت!‬
‫- أحسنت‬
‫وإن سرق أحد آخر المصرف قبل وصولهم؟‬
‫من عساه يفعل ذلك سيد "رانغو"؟‬
‫كنت آمل أن تخبرني بنفسك‬
‫يبدو لي ذلك أشبه باتهام‬
‫اعتبره ما تشاء‬
‫هناك شيء قلته لي ما زال يتردد في ذهني‬
‫ما هو؟‬
‫من يتحكم بالماء... يتحكم بكل شيء‬
‫بربّك سيد "رانغو"‬
‫توكل إلي قدرة إلهية‬
‫كيف عساي أتحكّم بالماء؟‬
‫من الواضح أنك برعت جيدا في هذه اللعبة‬
‫حسنا، أمارسها منذ أعوام عدة سيدي‬
‫كنت هنا قبل أن شق الطريق العام‬
‫هذا الوادي الكبير‬
‫رأيت سير التقدّم‬
‫وتعلّمت بعض الأمور‬
‫قد يكون حان الوقت لتنظر إلى أبعد من ذلك‬
‫ان تبدأ بتقدير مجرى التاريخ الشاسع‬
‫انظر هناك بني‬
‫تكاد ترى مرور الوقت‬
‫ماذا تبني هناك؟‬
‫المستقبل سيد "رانغو"، المستقبل‬
‫قريبا، سيختفي كل ذلك ويغدو أسطورة‬
‫بلدة الحدود، رجل القانون، المسلّح‬
‫ما عاد هناك مكان لهم‬
‫- أصبحنا متمدّنين الآن‬
‫-هذا صحيح، متمدّنين‬
‫هذا ما يحمله المستقبل، كن جزءا منه‬
‫أو تكون مستثنى منه‬
‫هذا ما حصل للسيد "ميريماك"؟ جرى استثناؤه؟‬
‫سيد "رانغو" تنسى أنك مجرد عظاية صغيرة‬
‫يبدو أنك تنسى أنني رجل القانون‬
‫في هذه الانحاء‬
‫كان شريفنا الجديد يؤدي دور البطل لوقت طويل‬
‫بحيث بدأ يصدّق ذلك‬
‫ناد "جايك" الأفعى المجلجلة‬
‫لكن "جايك" هو ملاك الموت‬
‫لا يرحل أبدا بدون قتل أحد‬
‫افعل ذلك!‬
‫اهدأ، عليك أن تبدو مرتّبا لتلقى خالقك‬
‫وصل الموت‬
‫كيف سينجو البطل؟‬
‫اشترى العمدة الأرض بكاملها في الوادي‬
‫باستثناء مزرعتك آنسة "فاصوليا"‬
‫هذا مناف للمنطق، بدون ماء تلك الأرض‬
‫بلا جدوى‬
‫ما لم يتمكن من التحكم بالماء‬
‫كمثانة القرد، سيعيدها ما أن يشتري كل الأرض‬
‫لكن كيف يتحكم بالماء؟‬
‫شريف، لدينا مشكلة‬
‫انتظري "فاصوليا"، لن يكون ذلك ضروريا‬
‫-اشنقه حتى يزرق لونه!‬
‫-أعطونا السارقين!‬
‫اهدؤوا، دعوني أتكلم!‬
‫- ثبّتهم بمسامير على باب المحكمة‬
‫- اهدؤوا‬
‫أحضرهم إلى هنا لكي نقطع أعضاءهم الحميمة‬
‫أنت أيضا "سبونز"؟‬
‫أخذوا هذه المياه، أخذوا كل ما لدينا!‬
‫ما دمت الشريف، لن يشنق أحد‬
‫لكنها غلطته!‬
‫قلت إنك ستعيد الماء‬
‫بدون هذه المياه لا أمل لنا‬
‫لا يبقى لنا ما نؤمن به‬
‫أترون هذه الشارة هناك؟‬
‫ما دام هناك شريف، سيسود النظام في البلدة‬
‫لكن بدون نظام... فكروا مليّا، أجل‬
‫يبدأ الأمر ببطء، كالفطر‬
‫يصدر جدال غاضب، تليه اتهامات‬
‫ينقلب الجار على جاره وسرعان ما...‬
‫نأكل أولادنا، تتزاوج الكلاب والهررة‬
‫لخلق شذوذ متحوّلة غير طبيعية!‬
‫تريد أن تؤمن بشيء "سبونز"؟‬
‫آمن بي‬
‫آمن بهذه الشارة‬
‫ما دامت معلّقة...‬
‫لدينا أمل‬
‫مرحبا يا أخي‬
‫أنت عطش؟‬
‫مرّ وقت طويل يا أخي‬
‫كيف حالك؟‬
‫تعلم‬
‫يبدو أنك تخبرهم كيف قتلت الأخوة "جنكنز"‬
‫برصاصة واحدة، صحيح؟‬
‫أليس هذا صحيحا؟‬
‫كل هؤلاء الأشخاص الطيبون‬
‫يصدّقون قصصك، لا؟‬
‫يخالونك قاتلا بارد الدم، صحيح؟‬
‫يبدو أنهم يثقون بك‬
‫يعتقدون أنك ستنقذ بلدتهم الصغيرة‬
‫يعتقدون أنك ستنقذ أرواحهم!‬
‫لكننا نعرف غير ذلك، صحيح؟‬
‫لم لا تظهر لأصدقائك ما أنت مصنوع منه؟‬
‫أرهم من تكون فعلا‬
‫لم لا تخرج سلاحك وتطلق علي النار؟‬
‫لكن طبعا، لن تحتاج إلى كل هذه‬
‫واحدة فقط، صحيح؟‬
‫هيا أيها البطل، اضغط على الزناد‬
‫هل أنت قاتل، بني؟‬
‫لا أرى ذلك‬
‫لم ترتكب شيئا مما قلته، صحيح؟‬
‫لم تقتل الأخوة "جنكنز"، لست من الغرب!‬
‫أليس كذلك؟‬
‫قلها!‬
‫ارفع صوتك، لا أظن أن أصدقاءك سمعوك‬
‫لا‬
‫لم تفعل سوى الكذب على هؤلاء الناس الطيّبين‬
‫أنت محتال وجبان، أليس كذلك؟‬
‫-أعلى!‬
‫- أجل‬
‫اسمعني جيدا أيها المحتال المثير للشفقة‬
‫أصبحت هذه البلدة لي الآن‬
‫وإن رأيتك مجددا، سأرسل روحك إلى الجحيم!‬
‫من أنت؟‬
‫من أنا؟‬
‫أنا نكرة‬
‫حرّاس ذهبيون‬
‫عربة المرمر‬
‫روح الغرب‬
‫عذرا؟ سيدي... الروح، عذرا؟‬
‫هذا جميل، أحيانا عليك الحفر عميقا‬
‫لتجد ما تبحث عنه‬
‫إذا نجحت في المجيء‬
‫هذه الجنة؟‬
‫لو كانت كذلك، كنا نأكل الفطائر‬
‫مع "كيم نوفاك"‬
‫حقا، ماذا تفعل هنا؟‬
‫أبحث مثلك تماما‬
‫لا أعرف ما أبحث عنه حتى‬
‫ما عدت أعرف من أنا‬
‫كانوا ينادونك "الرجل المجهول الاسم"‬
‫والآن، بات لديهم اسم لكل شيء تقريبا‬
‫لا يهم ما ينادونك به، أعمال المرء هي الأهم‬
‫أجل لكن أعمالي زادت الأمور سوءا، أنا محتال‬
‫مزيّف!‬
‫يؤمن أصدقائي بي لكنهم بحاجة إلى بطل‬
‫إذا كن بطلا‬
‫لا تفهم، لا يفترض بي حتى أن أكون هنا‬
‫هذا صحيح، قطعت مسافة بعيدة لتجد ما ليس هنا‬
‫ألا ترى؟ لا يتعلق الأمر بك‬
‫يتعلق الأمر بهم‬
‫لكنني لا أستطيع العودة‬
‫لا أظن أنه لديك الخيار بني‬
‫لا يمكن لأي شخص أن يترك قصته‬
‫إذا نجحت‬
‫هذا صحيح يا صديقي، الطرف الآخر من الطريق‬
‫هل رأيت هذا؟‬
‫يرى كل منا ما يحتاج إلى رؤيته‬
‫هذا جميل، أليس كذلك؟‬
‫أجل‬
‫هذا جميل‬
‫تعال يا صديقي، أريد أن أريك شيئا‬
‫منذ أعوام عدة، كان هذا الوادي مغطى بالماء‬
‫حاليا، لم يبق سوى سؤال واحد‬
‫أين ذهبت الماء؟‬
‫إنهم يتبعون الماء‬
‫إنهم يتبعون الماء، هيا بنا!‬
‫هذا مناف للمنطق‬
‫بدون ماء، الأرض بلا جدوى‬
‫ماذا تبني هنا؟‬
‫المستقبل سيد "رانغو"‬
‫يمكنك أن تكون جزءا منه...‬
‫أو تكون مستثنى منه‬
‫كنت هنا قبل أن يشق الطريق العام‬
‫هذا الوادي الكبير‬
‫رأيت سير التقدم وتعلّمت بعض الأمور‬
‫تحكّم بالماء...‬
‫تتحكم بكل شيء‬
‫بربّك سيد "رينغو" توكل إلي قدرة إلهية‬
‫كيف عساني أتحكم بالماء؟‬
‫نظام الإقفال الطارئ‬
‫والآن يا صديقي؟‬
‫لا يمكن لأي كان أن يترك قصته‬
‫سأعود‬
‫لكن لماذا؟‬
‫لأن هذا ما أنا عليه‬
‫تتمتع بجرأة كبيرة للعودة يا رجل القانون‬
‫ماذا تريد؟‬
‫والدك والشبان سيشنقون بسبب عمل لم يرتكبوه‬
‫لكن لدي خطة‬
‫اعلم أن الامر صعب عليك "فاصوليا"‬
‫لكنك تتخذين قرارا عمليا‬
‫قرارات، قرارات‬
‫لا داعي لمزيد من العذاب‬
‫مزرعة عائلتك ليست سوى أرض قاحلة الآن‬
‫وقّعي العقد وخلّصي نفسك من عبء والدك‬
‫لم يكن أبي عبئا!‬
‫احتفظ بمال الدم خاصتك وسأحتفظ بأرضي!‬
‫افعلي ما يطلبه وإلا بحق نار الجحيم‬
‫سأقتلع عينيك البنيتين الجميلتين من رأسك!‬
‫لحظة"جايك"، لا داعي لأن...‬
‫دعني أقوم بعملي، أحضرتني إلى هنا‬
‫سنذهب حتى النهاية!‬
‫وقّعي هذه الورقة اللعينة يا امرأة!‬
‫اذهب إلى الجحيم!‬
‫من أين تخالينني جئت؟‬
‫انظري إلى عيني‬
‫أريد رؤيتك تموتين‬
‫"جايك"!‬
‫هيا إلى الخارج!‬
‫بات هذا اليوم أكثر إثارة للاهتمام‬
‫ضعها أرضا‬
‫وإلا ماذا ستفعل أيها الصغير؟ ستقتلني؟‬
‫هذا صحيح‬
‫-انزعا حوافركما القذرة عني!‬
‫-أقفلي فمك!‬
‫حسنا أيها الشريف، افعل ما جئت لأجله‬
‫بنك القذارة‬
‫الآن يا أصدقائي!‬
‫ارفعوا، ارفعوا!‬
‫كانت فكرة سيئة‬
‫أنت عطش، يا أخي؟‬
‫ها قد أتت!‬
‫إنها أعجوبة!‬
‫انتباه!‬
‫-انظر هنا!‬
‫- ما هذا؟‬
‫هذا خلاصنا يا أبي!‬
‫انها عملية فرار أيها الشبان، سنهرب!‬
‫سأحدث فيك ثقوبا كثيرة‬
‫بحيث أنك سترشح رصاصا‬
‫من أحشائك!‬
‫إذا من الجيد أنني أحضرت الدعم‬
‫ماذا؟‬
‫ليس صقرا‬
‫ليست سوى خفافيش!‬
‫التزموا بالخطة أيها الشبان، لننزفه بالكامل‬
‫لا يلزمني سوى رصاصة‬
‫لا تجرؤ على ذلك‬
‫جرّبني‬
‫سيد "رانغو"‬
‫ألم تنس شيئا؟‬
‫أعطني مسدسك أيها الشريف‬
‫حالا سيد "رانغو"‬
‫فاصوليا لا تقلقي، لدي خطة‬
‫النجدة!‬
‫افتحوا الباب!‬
‫حسنا، الخطة "ب"‬
‫فاصوليا أنت تتمتمين‬
‫حللت جميع مشاكلي باستثناء واحدة‬
‫هذا غرب جديد "جايك"‬
‫لا مكان للمسلّحين بعد الآن، نحن رجال أعمال‬
‫أجل، لدينا قبعات جديدة‬
‫في دياري، هذا ما نسمّيه الارتجال‬
‫لقد عدت‬
‫ما كان ذلك؟!‬
‫لا تصابي بالهلع لكنك ابتلعت لتوك الخطة "ب"‬
‫ماذا؟‬
‫حسنا، حان وقت الهلع‬
‫أنت والشريف متشابهان، لستما سوى أسطورتين‬
‫قريبا، لن يعود أحد يؤمن بوجودكما‬
‫رصاصة أخيرة لقتل آخر خارج على القانون‬
‫كم هذا مناسب‬
‫أيها الشريف أنا واثق أننا إن عملنا معا‬
‫سنجد حلا للوضع الحالي يناسبنا نحن الاثنين‬
‫حري بك أن تناقشه معه‬
‫رصاصة واحدة‬
‫سأسحب قبعتي تقديرا لك‬
‫من أسطورة لأخرى‬
‫ماذا قلت؟‬
‫قريبا، لن يعود أحد يؤمن بوجودك‬
‫لا "جايك"، لا!‬
‫"رانغو"!‬
‫أعدت الماء، كما وعدتنا‬
‫أنت بالفعل بطل‬
‫حسنا في ما يتعلق بالأبطال، حين...‬
‫لا تفسد الأمر‬
‫حسنا‬
‫لا أعلم بشأنكما لكنني أرغب في السباحة‬
‫وهكذا أنهت العظاية رحلتها‬
‫من بداية متواضعة إلى الأسطورة‬
‫التي نتغنّى بها اليوم‬
‫ومع أنه سيموت حتما‬
‫ربما إثر حادث منزلي، الذي يشكّل‬
‫٦٥% من الوفيات غير الطبيعيات‬
‫سيذكر سكان القرية دائما‬
‫اسم الذي أنقذهم‬
‫"رانغو"!‬